<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.7.1" created="2017-01-25 08:30" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Stock Forecast Based On a Predictive Algorithm &#124; I Know First  &#124;</title>
	<link>https://iknowfirst.com</link>
	<description>Stock Forecast Based On a Predictive Algorithm. Contact Us: contact@iknowfirst.com</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://iknowfirst.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://iknowfirst.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>33</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[Jacky]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[jackybraun@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Jacky]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>63</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[David Shabotinsky]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[dshabotinsky@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[David Shabotinsky]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[David]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Shabotinsky]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>69</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg@csuglobal.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>66</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[jacob.saphir]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[jacob_saphir@Yahoo.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[jacob.saphir]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>74</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[Barbara]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[barbara_1308@hotmail.fr]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Barbara Chouraqui]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Barbara]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Chouraqui]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>73</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[marika]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[marika.nicastro@post.idc.ac.il]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[marika nicastro]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[marika]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[nicastro]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>75</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[felipe]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[spritzer@poli.ufrj.br]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Felipe Spritzer]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Felipe]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Spritzer]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<wp:category>
		<wp:term_id>50</wp:term_id>
		<wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[algorithmic-articles]]></wp:category_nicename>
		<wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent>
		<wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></wp:cat_name>
	</wp:category>

	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>http://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-logo_IMG-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Stock Forecast Based On a Predictive Algorithm | I Know First  |</title>
	<link>https://iknowfirst.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">91248828</site>
	<item>
		<title>Stock Market Forecast: Creating a Model for Chaos Mapping and Predictions</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/stock-market-forecast-creating-a-model-for-chaos-mapping-and-predictions</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 08:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jacky]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iknowfirst.com/?p=31191</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="wp-image-30269 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/tali.png" alt="tali" width="50" height="50" /><em>Tali </em><i>Soroker</i><em> is a Financial Analyst at I Know First.</em>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Stock Market Forecast</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Chaotic systems revisited – see original article<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/machine-learning-trading-stock-market-and-chaos"> <u>here</u></a></li>
 	<li>Understanding the stock market as a chaotic process</li>
 	<li>What is a model and what is a multivariate time series?</li>
 	<li>How is machine learning used to create an efficient/effective model For stock market forecast</li>
 	<li>Considering higher dimension data sets and time complexity</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-31212 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/ai-power-logo.jpg" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="500" height="374" /></a></p>
<strong>Stock Market Forecast: Brief Review of Chaotic Processes</strong>

Ask any person on the street if something is random or chaotic and they may assume the two are synonymous. However, there is a very important distinction between the two types of processes, making it possible to make predictions for chaos while for randomness we cannot. Chaotic systems have the important property that each future event depends on past and current events. Using this, we can create models of chaotic systems in order to make predictions about future events. Models can be created using statistical analysis or, to avoid the difficulty involved in these problems, we can create a model for stock market forecast using machine learning and artificial intelligence.

<strong>Stock Market as a Chaotic Process</strong>

The stock market is a complex chaotic system. While markets exhibit many of the properties of chaotic systems, there are also other factors to consider. Market behavior displays aspects of both systemic and random components, which is what allows us to make realistic stock market forecasts with a decent degree of precision. In regards to the stock market, the chaos that we see is a consequence of the psychology of trading, something that we know is often times irrational. The irrationality of human psychology is not entirely predictable, however, there are underlying economic principles and assumptions that tell us how people will likely react to market change. Patterns form in the data over longer periods of time, and these patterns are crucial for the functionality of our chaos model.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-31199" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/AI-colors-11.jpg" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="348" height="349" /></a>

<strong>Stock Market Forecast: Creating a Model </strong>

We construct and use models in an attempt to explain some unknown phenomena in terms of what we do know. The most useful models are those that we can represent as mathematical equations. Possibly the most famous example of such a model is Albert Einstein’s model of mass-energy equivalence, better known as the equation, <em><strong>E</strong></em> = mc<sup>2</sup>.  Mathematicians create models all the time, trying to understand new concepts and hypotheses.

For this process to be effective in eventually reaching an understanding, these models must be testable. Just as in the scientific method, mathematicians must be able to put forward a potential model, test it, and have the ability to find a negative answer. Due to the chaotic nature of the systems that these models are attempting to explain, it is not necessary for there to be an exact fit with the data being analyzed. However, there should be at least some connection with the phenomena being exhibited. The best of the best should not only have decent precision but predictive capabilities as well.

When creating a model of complex phenomena, such as the stock market, one should begin by collecting all available information that is relevant in any way to the outcome of a situation. Once the data is gathered, it needs to be organized and one or more equations can be constructed that attempt to model the system. A simple example of this process can be seen below. On the left, there is a scatter plot of our “relevant data,” on the right we’ve drawn a line of best fit that can represent this data. We can then determine the equation of the line and use it to model our data. This basic principle is impossible for humans to employ for such systems as complex as the stock market, there are simply too many factors involved. Using artificial intelligence, we are able to make models for immense data sets with a similar, but more complicated method.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="alignnone wp-image-31286 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/1.1.jpg" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="841" height="545" /></a>

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-31287" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/1.2.jpg" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="840" height="544" />

<strong>Multivariate time Series</strong>

The simple definition of a time series is a series of values that are measuring some system and are obtained at successive times, often with a set interval between them. Time series can be univariate or they can be multivariate. These terms are not referring to the number of independent variables in the time series, as one may think. These terms are referring, in a general sense, to the ways in which the data sets are relating to each other. Imagine somebody is charting the heights and weights of people over a certain period of time. In a univariate model of this information, there is no interaction between the height and weight of a person, while in a multivariate model the two sets of data are charted together and the correlation between the two can be examined. This example is useful for seeing the benefits of a multivariate examination, as we know that the weight of a person generally increases as their height increases. We know that there is a correlation between the two, and it is helpful to be able to analyze it.

The stock market operates as a multivariate system. The Dow Jones (DJI), one of the oldest market indices with a daily value representation, and gold prices are both examples of time series. The two are related, but it is unclear in what way they are affecting each other. To use a univariate system to model the two would be a mistake as the relation that they have to each other would not be able to be examined or understood. By aligning them together on one chart, one can see their inter-relation and make an attempt to construct a model. The complexity of the stock market means that there are many more examples of systems working together in ways that we are unable to see without the help of modeling.

<strong>Machine Learning</strong>

Once the model is built, it must be tested using real data. Multiple models are tested against each other with a “fitness function” being used to compare the models and check for accuracy. This function will evaluate how “good” each potential solution is compared to the others. After the function evaluates the data, it returns a positive integer called a “fitness value”, that shows how accurate the model is.

Here, machine learning comes into play in a major way. Once fitness values are found for potential solutions, they go through a process of natural selection to select which solutions survive and are passed on to the next generation and which do not. This process is not as simple as selecting the top ‘x’ number of solutions with the highest fitness values, the solutions are chosen statistically with a higher fitness value increasing the statistical weight of a given solution. So, the higher the fitness value of a solution, the higher the chance that it will survive, but it is not certain.

As the natural selection process continues, just as in the natural world, the machine is learning and parameters of the models are being optimized to improve performance. The mechanism of machine learning should allow for testing and screening of different models to occur simultaneously with the proposal of new improved models.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-31201 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/24.jpg" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="867" height="781" />

The algorithm’s key principle is based on the fact that a stock’s price is a function of many factors that interact with each other non-linearly. Real-life examples generally will not fit a simple linear model because they often exhibit the reversal of a trend after a particular saturation point. Artificial neural networks and genetic algorithms work much better for modeling these systems because they allow for this reversal phenomena.

<strong>Dimensionality Reduction</strong>

Dimensionality reduction is a crucial part of building a credible and efficient model for the given system. Reducing the number of random variables that the algorithm is considering and processing speeds up the machine’s execution and improves performance. The goal here is to leave as few variables as possible while losing a negligible amount of accuracy.

Principle Component Analysis (PCA) is just one method of dimensionality reduction. PCA works by taking the n-dimensional data set and orthogonally transforming the data into a new set of n coordinates called “Principle Components”. The first principle component will be determined by accounting for the most variation that exists in the data set. Each succeeding component will have the next highest variance; all components will be orthogonal to each other as well. The goal here is to reduce the dimensionality of the data set by taking these principal components that represent the highest amount of variance and to disregard the components that are not representing prominent variance.

<img class="wp-image-31202 size-full aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/37.png" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="400" height="318" />

Other notable methods of dimensionality reduction include applying a low variance filter or a high correlation filter, pruning the network, and adding and replacing inputs. Clustering can also be used for dimensionality reduction, or it can be a goal on its own. Clustering involves separating given sets of examples into sets of “similar” examples. This process is a good way to create structure among the observed data which is helpful for summarizing large and unmanageable data sets.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-31203 " src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/44.png" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="691" height="744" />

<strong>Time Constraint</strong>

When creating a model for systems with substantial data sets, the amount of time that is required for the algorithm to make all of the necessary calculations can be extensive. If the model is too complicated, it may not be able to solve the problem is its entirety, making it completely impractical. Models must then be created with a certain time constraint. As Einstein once said, “the model should be simple, but not too simple.” We want to restrict the parameters to create a model that is simple enough that it can operate without losing crucial information.

As we make restrictions on the parameters, compromises must be made. Speed, precision, and generality are all competing with each other and one must prioritize in order to optimize the model. Time complexity, commonly expressed in big O notation, of an algorithm, quantifies the amount of time that is needed as a function of the input. Often times the time complexity is estimated using the worst-case time complexity because the algorithm’s performance can vary based on different input types.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-31204 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/53.jpg" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="608" height="432" />

<strong>Conclusion</strong>

As a chaotic system, the stock market contains patterns that can be analyzed with models. Algorithms can be designed to make predictions about the stock market. Machine learning is incorporated into the model and is used for testing and optimizing the solution. As the model is being created, many factors must be considered such as the dimensions of the data and the algorithm’s time complexity. In order to have a workable model, compromises will need to be made in some cases in order to find a balance between speed, precision, and generality. I Know First has successfully created an algorithm to model the stock market and to make predictions on trends in the stock market over 6 different time horizons.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-31205 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/63.png" alt="Stock Market Forecast" width="1147" height="432" />

Part 1 <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/machine-learning-trading-stock-market-and-chaos">Click Here</a>

<iframe style="border: none;" src="http://www.slideshare.net/iknowfirst/slideshelf" width="490px" height="470px" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>

&nbsp;

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="wp-image-30269 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/tali.png" alt="tali" width="50" height="50" /><em>Tali </em><i>Soroker</i><em> is a Financial Analyst at I Know First.</em>
<br><br><br>

<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Chaotic systems revisited – see original article<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/machine-learning-trading-stock-market-and-chaos"> <u>here</u></a></li>
 	<li>Understanding the stock market as a chaotic process</li>
 	<li>What is a model and what is a multivariate time series?</li>
 	<li>How is machine learning used to create an efficient/effective model For stock market forecast</li>
 	<li>Considering higher dimension data sets and time complexity</li>
</ul>


<strong><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/stock-market-forecast-creating-a-model-for-chaos-mapping-and-predictions">
</a></strong>
<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/stock-market-forecast-creating-a-model-for-chaos-mapping-and-predictions"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/stock-market-forecast-creating-a-model-for-chaos-mapping-and-predictions">
</a></h2>



Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">Here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>31191</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-17 10:34:12]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-17 08:34:12]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[stock-market-forecast-creating-a-model-for-chaos-mapping-and-predictions]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="chaos"><![CDATA[CHAOS]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="stock-market-forecast"><![CDATA[stock market forecast]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Stock Market Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485363993;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:30267;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:4201;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:1769;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Stock Market Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:3;s:9:"pinterest";i:1;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[swp_open_graph_image_data]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[["https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/artic.jpg",1000,405,false]]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_totes]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[swp_open_thumbnail_url]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[swp_cache_timestamp]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[410578]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_facebook_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Top 3 Stock Valuation Methods Plus the Algorithmic Valuation Tool</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/top-3-stock-valuation-methods-plus-algorithmic-valuation-tool</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 12:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jacky]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iknowfirst.com/?p=37558</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="wp-image-30269 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/tali.png" alt="tali" width="50" height="50" />Tali </em><i>Soroker</i><em> is a Financial Analyst at I Know First.</em>

&nbsp;

&nbsp;
<h2>Stock Valuation Methods</h2>
<em>May 24th, 2016</em>

<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>What is stock valuation?</li>
 	<li>Absolute Valuation versus Relative Valuation</li>
 	<li>Examples of Valuation Methods</li>
 	<li>Stock Valuation with the Algorithm</li>
 	<li>New Fundamental Package!</li>
</ul>
<strong>Stock Valuation</strong>

The share prices for assets vary not only on a day-to-day basis but on a minute-to-minute and even second-to-second basis. There are many reasons for these fluctuations in prices, but it essentially comes down to the inability to discover the true value of any asset. Prices for assets constantly overshoot or undershoot an imaginary point of equilibrium called the “fair price”.

As share prices fluctuate daily, investors and analysts do what is called stock valuation in order to determine the essential value of particular stock or asset. There are innumerable valuation techniques that can be used for this determination as each stock is unique and each industry has unique properties that need to be taken into account.

Valuation methods can be divided into two basic categories: Absolute Valuation and Relative Valuation.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-37568" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/multiple-valuation-methods.jpg" alt="Stock Valuation Methods" width="1000" height="666" /></a>

<strong>Absolute Valuation</strong>

Absolute valuation strictly consists of the fundamentals of the asset that is being analyzed, without taking into account comparable assets within the same industry. Some of the most common fundamentals that analysts look at include the company’s cash flow, profit retention, and gross margins. By looking at a company’s fundamentals, investors can examine the overall “health” of the company and determine the value of the stock.

Investors, then, are looking at key factors in the company such as dividends, gross margins, and cash flow. Some of the most common methods of determining a stock’s absolute value include using discounted cash flow (DCF) analysis and the dividend discount model (DDM).

The <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/dcf.asp?layout=orig">discounted cash flow method</a> involves using future free cash flow projections and applies discounts to them in order to arrive at an estimation of the company’s current value. This estimation is then used to evaluate whether there is potential for an investment to see growth. When the current value that is calculated is higher than the actual current cost of the asset, there is an assumption that the market will move upward to correct the gap in stock price and stock value. While DCF models are a powerful tool for stock valuation, there is a possibility for error based on chosen inputs and even small changes in inputs can cause major discretions in the estimated value that is found.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-37561 " src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Discount-Cash-Flow.jpg" alt="stock valuation methods" width="401" height="169" /></a>

Investors using the <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/ddm.asp?layout=orig">dividend discount model</a> use a similar discounting method, but look at predicted dividends rather than future cash flow.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-37562" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Dividend-Discount-Method.jpg" alt="stock valuation methods" width="500" height="136" /></a>

<strong>Relative Valuation</strong>

Relative valuation methods, on the other hand, involves comparing the relative strength of a company to those within its industry. The process involves company fundamentals such as price-to-earnings (P/E) multiples, price-to-sales (P/S), and price-to-cash flow (P/CF). Once calculated, these ratios can be used to compare different companies. Of these, the P/E ratio is the most commonly used because a company’s earnings are a major driver of the stock price.

A company’s <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/p/price-earningsratio.asp?layout=orig">price-to-earnings ratio</a> is calculated by dividing the market value per share by the company’s earnings per share (EPS). The EPS is most commonly found from the last four quarters, which is used to find the trailing P/E ratio, but it can also be taken from estimates of future earnings; this form of P/E ratio is called projected or forward P/E. Whether using a trailing P/E or a forward P/E ratio, the number represents the dollar amount that an investor should invest in order to expect one dollar of the company’s earnings.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-37563" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/PE-ratio.jpg" alt="stock valuation method" width="501" height="118" /></a>

There are three possibilities for a company’s P/E ratio, it can be high, low, or negative. If the P/E ratio is high, it indicates that the stock is trading for a high price and/or the company’s earnings are relatively low. It shows that investors are paying a premium for lower earnings, which could indicate that the company is set to see higher growth in the future, or the earnings are stable and risk is low. Another possibility is that the stock is overvalued. Conversely, when the ratio is low, the share value is low and earnings are high relative to each other. This could mean that the stock is undervalued and that the share price will increase. But this could also mean that the company is now in trouble, the stock price has fallen, which is reflected in the low current price per past earnings patio, but the future earnings are not assured. There are various methods to help distinguish between these opposite possibilities. In the case that a company is not producing positive earnings, the P/E ratio is not useful and is marked as N/A.

The average market price-to-earnings ratio lies somewhere between 15 and 25 times earnings, but P/E ratios tend to vary between industries, so they are most useful in comparing the ratios between different companies in the same sector.

<strong>Valuation from the Predictive Algorithm</strong>

I Know First’s <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">machine-learning algorithm</a> uses relative valuation methods to analyze assets across more than 3,000 different markets. The algorithm is consuming and utilizing data, not just from individual companies, but from the full market spectrum. The assumption is that the market itself is the best entity to examine for price discovery, and not a spreadsheet that doesn’t include all of the relevant information. Even all three of these top valuation methods are combined, the actual stock value may not be accurately reflected. There are many inputs that are missing from the analysis, and in some cases non-objective factors determine a stock’s price more than company fundamentals. Apple, for example, has a reputation with consumers and if that reputation is damaged it will dramatically affect the stock price despite company cash flow, dividends, etc. With the extensive range of data that is inputted into the algorithm, the system is able to produce forecasts not only for company stocks, but for currency pairs, commodities, and even the S&amp;P 500 which is commonly used as a benchmark for the state of the economy as a whole.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-37564" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/ikf-algo.png" alt="stock valuation methods" width="1147" height="432" /></a>

At the end say that all these combined to not accurately reflect the actual value. There is a lot of inputs that are missing, because they are subject to non-objective interpretation, such as the value of intangibles, IP (intellectual property). Sometimes a company is a sum of parts (business units), and a part could be more valuable if it was on it's own. All these can affect the final score.

<strong>I Know First’s New ‘Fundamentals’ Algorithmic Filter</strong>

Our R&amp;D team recently added a <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/introducing-the-new-fundamental-analysis-filter-to-the-i-know-first-algorithm">new stock package</a> using a fundamentals filter. This new forecasting package includes algorithmic forecasts for stocks based on several fundamental criteria. Investors can choose to filter stocks based on high and low values for the following four valuation indicators:
<ul>
 	<li>P/E (price-to-earnings ratio)</li>
 	<li>PEG (price/earnings-to-growth ratio)</li>
 	<li>price-to-book ratio</li>
 	<li>price-to-sales ratio</li>
</ul>
Additionally, our institutional clients can customize their forecasts to be screened for the valuation indicators that are most relevant to their personal trading strategy.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-37056" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/fundamental.jpg" alt="stock valuation methods" width="368" height="384" /></a>

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="wp-image-30269 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/tali.png" alt="tali" width="50" height="50" /><em>Tali </em><i>Soroker</i><em> is a Financial Analyst at I Know First.</em>
<h2></h2>

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/top-3-stock-valuation-methods-plus-algorithmic-valuation-tool"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-37568" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/multiple-valuation-methods.jpg" alt="Stock Valuation Methods" width="1000" height="666" /></a>

<strong><a href="http://iknowfirst.com/top-3-stock-valuation-methods-plus-algorithmic-valuation-tool">
</a></strong>
<h2><a href="http://iknowfirst.com/top-3-stock-valuation-methods-plus-algorithmic-valuation-tool"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="http://iknowfirst.com/top-3-stock-valuation-methods-plus-algorithmic-valuation-tool">
</a></h2>


Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">Here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>37558</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-22 14:55:58]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-22 12:55:58]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[top-3-stock-valuation-methods-plus-algorithmic-valuation-tool]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="multiple-valuation-methods"><![CDATA[multiple valuation methods]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="stock-valuation"><![CDATA[Stock Valuation]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="stock-valuation-methods"><![CDATA[stock valuation methods]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="valuation-methods"><![CDATA[valuation methods]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[stock valuation methods]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[stock valuation methods]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[81]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485296239;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:31979;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:19795;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:20528;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:1;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quantum Trading: Econophysics Can Help Predict Financial Markets</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-quantum-trading-econophysics-can-help-predict-financial-markets</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shabotinsky]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iknowfirst.com/?p=90605</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class=" wp-image-29347 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/dr-roitman.png" alt="dr roitman" width="59" height="61" />This article was co-authored by Dr. Roitman, Co-Founder &amp; CTO of I Know First Ltd. With over 35 years of research in AI and machine learning. Dr. Roitman earned a Ph.D  from the Weizmann Institute of Science.</em>

&nbsp;

<em><img class="wp-image-42826 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Profile-Picutre-real-300x300.png" width="50" height="50" />This article was co-authored by David Shabotinsky, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled at an undergraduate Finance program at the Interdisciplinary Center, Herzliya.</em>

&nbsp;
<h2>Quantum Trading</h2>
Summary:
<ul>
 	<li>How Econophysics has shaped to become an important field of study for financial markets and policy makers</li>
 	<li>The uncertainty principle and how its used to predict the financial markets, such as bear and bull markets</li>
 	<li>What is phase transition in physics and how can it be applied to the financial market</li>
 	<li>Real applications of Econophysics in finance and policy making today</li>
 	<li>I Know First's self-learning predictive algorithm and its application of phase transition</li>
 	<li>Real differentiated competitive advantages offered by I Know First's algorithmic solutions</li>
</ul>
<strong>Background</strong>

Though many wouldn’t think of the financial market and physicists being much related, Econophysics, a relatively new field of study, is proving how the notions in physics are able to explain phenomenon in the financial market that baffles investors. This combination between physics and finance/economics, allows the business world to better tackle various risks found in finance.

An Oxford University professor J Doyne Farmer <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/8461f5e6-35f5-11e3-952b-00144feab7de">explains that</a>, “Ultimately, our biggest interest is in providing a tool for policy makers for when they ask questions like: what restrictions should we place on markets? How much leverage should we let homebuyers have? Should we allow this type of loan? What would happen if there was a mass migration to that type of loan? Is that going to make the housing market more volatile or not? We think we can answer those questions,”

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-90606 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Picture1.png" alt="Quantum Trading" width="769" height="598" /></a>

<strong>Uncertainty Principle in The Market</strong>

Here we will examine two main approaches/principles in explaining the financial markets, phase transition and the uncertainty principle. The former is more popular in explaining many market phenomenon, i.e. explaining the market crash of 1987. The Uncertainty Principle is a broader idea, originally developed by Werner Heisenberg in quantum physics. He essentially explained that the more precisely one can identify the momentum of a particle, the less likely one can identify the position of that same particle. The vice versa applies for the being able to identify the position of a particle. This idea can be applied to better understanding the financial market. The implication of Heisenberg’s principle is that one must choose between being able to determine precisely the movement of say a stock, or the timing of a move (but not which direction). For example, many investors may exclaim that the market will move in an upward direction in the foreseeable future. However, this person cannot tell you the exact timing of the movement. Hence, when bullish or bearish investors place their bets, often times they may experience a short-term loss, but in the long-term be correct in their prediction.

The same holds true for the opposite, in detecting a time for a major movement in the stock market. For example, an upcoming ECB or Federal Reserve meeting tends to have a real impact on the price fluctuations in the financial market. However, one cannot predict with certainty which direction the prices will move, as it will vary depending on the news.

<strong>What is Phase Transition?</strong>

In physics, ‘Phase Transition’ can refer to the physical transition from one state to a different state within the same type of object. For example, if you take water as an element, with different temperature and pressure levels one can achieve a few different phases. It can go from an ice cube to water to then a gaseous state. The Triple Point is the combination of temperature and pressure that permits the coexistence of the three phases in dynamic equilibrium. A phase transition, (or phase change) is the transformation of a thermodynamic system from one phase to another. At the critical point (in the phase transition) the system is undergoing its change.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-90607 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/phasetransition.jpg" alt="phasetransition" width="1069" height="537" /></a>

<em>(Source: armstrongeconomics.com) </em>

Today, many experts explain market conditions through basic principles derived from phase transition. In the ‘market’ the price of an instrument is determined by supply and demand, in its most basic understanding, or buy and sell orders. For example, when demand rises for a security the price will generally rise as a result. In the market, there are essentially three phases that the market can transition through: wait, buy, and sell. These are determined by the demand/supply ratio of trading orders. At times a net demand of zero may exist, which is when the market enters the ‘wait’ phase. Therefore, when a positive net demand exists in the market, it is said to be apart of the ‘buy’ phase, which can be thought of as a gas state as there is a pressure on the price from below (having it rise). Additionally, when a negative net demand exists, this is considered part of the ‘sell’ phase in the market, or a liquid phase, as there is pressure on the price from above. Traders (investors) use analytical and critical skills of information available in the market, to determine orders to buy and/or sell securities. Hence, on a systematic level, the balance of these buy/sell orders determines the phase of the market at hand. At the critical point in the phase transition, the market essentially crashes as trade orders become mostly selling ones.

<strong>Applications of Econophysics In The Financial Arena</strong>

This principle of phase transition is studied by econophysicists and other scientists today using back-tests of historical empirical evidence found in the market. Today, many of what we know about the financial markets <a href="http://physicsoffinance.blogspot.co.il/2013/05/what-haseconophysics-achieved.html">can be attributed to this field of study</a>. For example, they have been able to further elaborate on the causes on financial crashes, and relate them not only to financial and economic principles, but as well to dynamical principles. Additionally, in collaboration with economists, they have been able to develop more realistic models of how the market functions. For example, in the mid-90s, researchers at the Santa Fe Institute explained how fat-tailed dynamics can interact with the market and actually arise naturally. This type of model and others have greatly been able to influence financial policy for both the private and public sector. The European Commission has used these types of models to influence their decision making with regard to various financial regulations and laws, such as the idea of a financial transactions tax.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-90608 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/econophysics-.jpeg" alt="econophysics" width="229" height="220" /></a>

For decades many esteemed economists have discussed the risks and negative externalities on the economy of high leverage techniques used by wall street, i.e. Leverage Buyouts (LBOs). The idea being that as companies take on higher levels of debt, their default rate becomes higher as well. Hence, any finance students can explain that firms should seek to maintain an appropriate level of debt/equity ratio. This continues to be a highlighting critique on the financial industry in its excessive use of debts and financial engineering. Physicists have helped clarify market instability. In that, many thought that derivatives and various risky financial instruments, when share in uniformity, can help make individual firms and banks safer. However, Econophysics found that risk sharing can actually decrease stability in the market. Additionally, today, it has become increasingly harder to determine the risks taken on by financial institutions, as they operate differently than the basic management type company. Econophysicists were able to develop a network measure called ‘Debtrank’, to better measure risks undertaken. It is able to cut through the vast networks of the financial institutions and reveal the true nature of the risks. For example, in the 2008 financial crisis many had underestimated in the impact of Lehman Brothers becoming bankrupts, as most could not comprehend risks of many of their products, such as derivatives, and they were interconnected on a macro level.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-90609 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/UPDATED_new-econophys-editorial-image.gif" alt="updated_new-econophys-editorial-image" width="600" height="478" /></a>
<h6><em>(Source: IOP Science)</em></h6>
<strong>I Know First’s Self-Learning Predictive Algorithm</strong>

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com">I Know First</a> has a state of the art <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">algorithm</a>, that uses Artificial Intelligence and self-learning capabilities to predict asset price movements in the market today. The algorithm as well incorporates models and concepts derived from phase transition. The concept of phase transition occurs mainly in conditions of market instability, which is analogous to supersaturation in physics. When one paradigm has been exhausted, and the conditions are ripe for a change, then any small perturbation in the market input, such as the interest rate change, or social event (presidential elections) can bring about a large paradigm shift. In contrast, the stable market is characterized by a smooth input-output relationship. The I Know First algorithm is measuring the current state of the market, and is capable of detecting the potential shift in paradigms. In a stable market if one modifies the input to the algorithm by a small amount, the output should change by a correspondingly small amount. On the other hand, when the market is unstable, a discontinuity occurs, a small change in the input could result in a drastically different output. Hence, many analysts especially econophysicists explain the financial crash of 1987 using phase transition.

The I Know First algorithm takes many different inputs to create an output, and the relationship between input and output is highly non-linear. To test the present conditions for instability one would normally need to modify each of the inputs by a small amount. The huge number of different permutations of these inputs would take impossibly long time to probe. But we also know that not all inputs are equal. Some are more important than others by the orders of magnitude. Also, we know the inter-relationship between these important inputs, which allows us to cut the probing experiments to manageable numbers. Thus by modifying these in a controlled fashion we can measure the market stability.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-90610 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/process.jpg" alt="process" width="1011" height="389" /></a>

<strong>I Know First's Competitive Advantages </strong>

There is still another way, which is already built into the I Know First forecast. It consists of two values, the signal and the predictability. The latter is a measure of the forecast performance in the recent past. By monitoring the performance of each stock and of the aggregate of stocks over time one can judge the stability of the market. The signal is an indicator which represents the predicted movement direction/trend; not a percentage or specific target price. The signal strength indicates how much the current price deviates from what the system considers an equilibrium or “fair” price. The predictability is a separate indicator that is obtained by calculating the correlation between the prediction and the actual asset movement for each discrete time period. The algorithm then averages the results of all the prediction points, while giving more weight to recent performance. As the machine keeps learning, the predictability values generally increase, but then stabilize. By monitoring the predictability over time, one can detect the potential paradigm shift. This is a part of the competitive advantage offered by I Know First, allowing investors to more successfully differentiate themselves in the market.

&nbsp;

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class=" wp-image-29347 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/dr-roitman.png" alt="dr roitman" width="59" height="61" />This article was co-authored by Dr. Roitman, Co-Founder &amp; CTO of I Know First Ltd. With over 35 years of research in AI and machine learning. Dr. Roitman earned a Ph.D  from the Weizmann Institute of Science.</em>

<br><br><br>

<em><img class="wp-image-42826 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Profile-Picutre-real-300x300.png" width="50" height="50" />This article was co-authored by David Shabotinsky, a Financial Analyst at <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled at an undergraduate Finance program at the Interdisciplinary Center, Herzliya.</em>

&nbsp;
<h2>Quantum Trading</h2>
Summary:
<ul>
 	<li>How Econophysics has shaped to become an important field of study for financial markets and policy makers</li>
 	<li>The uncertainty principle and how its used to predict the financial markets, such as bear and bull markets</li>
 	<li>What is phase transition in physics and how can it be applied to the financial market</li>
 	<li>Real applications of Econophysics in finance and policy making today</li>
 	<li>I Know First's self-learning predictive algorithm and its application of phase transition</li>
 	<li>Real differentiated competitive advantages offered by I Know First's algorithmic solutions</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href=" https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-quantum-trading-econophysics-can-help-predict-financial-markets"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-quantum-trading-econophysics-can-help-predict-financial-markets">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to our exclusive content in the PREMIUM section <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">Click Here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>90605</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-10 12:17:11]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-10 10:17:11]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsrar-quantum-trading-econophysics-can-help-predict-financial-markets]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="david-shabotinsky"><![CDATA[David Shabotinsky]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="dr-roitman"><![CDATA[Dr. Roitman]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="econophysics"><![CDATA[Econophysics]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="financial-market"><![CDATA[Financial Market]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="i-know-first-competitive-advantage"><![CDATA[I Know First Competitive advantage]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="phase-transition"><![CDATA[phase transition]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="stock-market-predictions"><![CDATA[stock market predictions]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="uncertainty-principle"><![CDATA[Uncertainty Principle]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Quantum Trading]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Quantum Trading]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[75]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485241256;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:855;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:43877;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91042;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:2;s:9:"pinterest";i:2;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Verizon Stock Forecast: 5G Developments and Acquisition</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-verizon-stock-forecast-5g-developments-and-acquisition</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 10:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92653</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" width="70" height="73" />This article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Verizon Stock Forecast</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Verizon (VZ) Stock Analysis</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For VZ</li>
</ul>
<strong>Verizon (VZ) Stock Analysis<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92655" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Verizon_Logo.svg_.png" alt="verizon stock analysis" width="350" height="202" /></a></strong>

Verizon Communications Inc. (Verizon), incorporated on October 7, 1983, is a holding company. The Company, through its subsidiaries, provides communications, information and entertainment services and products to consumers, businesses and governmental agencies. The Firm offers voice, data and video services and solutions on its wireless and wireline networks. The Company’s divisions include Wireless and Wireline. The Wireless segment offers communications services and products, including wireless voice and data services and equipment sales that are provided to consumer, business and government clients across the United States. The Wireline segment offers voice, data and video communications services and products, such as broadband video and data, corporate networking solutions, data center and cloud services, security and managed network services, and local and long distance voice services. The Firm provides these services and products to clients in the United States, as well as to carriers, businesses and government clients both in the United States and around the world.
Verizon is set to release its quarterly earnings on January 24, 2017. It is predicted that VZ will be up $0.90 EPS which is up 1.12% from its last years EPS of $0.89. The profit if reached will be $3.69 billion for the cell phone provider. Last quarter VZ reported an EPS of $1.01. Currently, 17 analysts have been covering VZ and out of those 17, 5 gave VZ a buy rating, 0 analysts gave it a sell rating and 12 analysts gave VZ a hold rating.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92687" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-01-at-1.39.20-PM.png" alt="Verizon Stock Forecast" width="348" height="343" /></a>

It is projected that Verizon price per share may range from a low of $44 and a high of $55 with an average of $51.39. As it currently stands, VZ's share price is $53.38, down from is previous close of $53.74. In VZ's Q3 earnings report, the company brought in $22.1 billion in revenue, compared to Q2 with 21.7 billion in revenue. However, there is a 55.56% chance that VZ revenue will go down in Q4 compared to Q3. In the last 27 quarters, VZ equity price has gone down in 15 quarter. In the last 3 years, the earnings per share have gone up 66%, above estimations. In the last year, there was an earnings surprise of 1.06%.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92688 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-01-at-1.47.36-PM.png" alt="screen-shot-2017-01-01-at-1-47-36-pm" width="291" height="271" /></a>

Verizon and its rival, AT&amp;T plan to release 5G technology within their broadband Internet. The new 5G technology will be able to deliver 10 times faster data to smartphones compared to the 4G. The delay on data will only be 1 millisecond. Though the release will be this year, it will only be to certain households and businesses with a true release in 2020. By that time, carriers and the government will have invested $5 billion into the 5G technology development. The network being released will use millimeter waves for 5G, millimeter waves are "waves transmitted at frequencies between 30 and 300 gigahertz, and they are between 1 and 10 millimeters in <a href="http://spectrum.ieee.org/telecom/wireless/verizon-and-att-prepare-to-bring-5g-to-market">length</a> These waves are much smaller than the ones used for 4G, the signals used for 4G is between 1 and 10 millimeters in length, with frequencies below 6 GHz. For the 5G network, carriers are turning their attention to 26 GHz waves, as well as a 15 GHz wave that will be tested in Austin, Texas.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92769" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/25472265426_9f41fe663e_b.jpg" alt="25472265426_9f41fe663e_b" width="355" height="236" /></a>

There are problems with achieving true 5G. Fixed Wireless Systems used by carriers send beams to connect to devices from a stationary point. The carriers have to run Ethernet cables from the stationary point, which could be from an antenna, to deliver the 5G Internet to stationary buildings. This is not a problem, however if the user is moving, whether it be walking or in a moving vehicle, it's not as simple as using Ethernet cables. Carriers are turning their attention to autonomous cars, connected appliances and robots in order to overcome the current issue with 5G. Another problem with the millimeter wave is that it isn't able to move through buildings because it is easily absorbed into water and oxygen molecules present in the air. To overcome this problem, the signal has to use more power than 4G just to be received on the users end. Another issue is that other companies may come out with technology that is better than the millimeter wave in a quicker timetable than the release in 2020, which would be a huge loss of investment.

Verizon is also moving forward with acquisition of Yahoo Inc. despite recent data breaches that have impacted millions of Yahoo's customers. The reason that Verizon doesn't seemed phased about this problem is that hackers are common in the corporate world and will continue to happen, even as Internet security continues to strengthen.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92768 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2000px-Yahoo_Logo.svg_.png" alt="2000px-yahoo_logo-svg" width="662" height="126" /></a>

Large companies that have been affected by hackers include Sony, Target, The Home Depot, JPMorgan Chase, Anthem, and Cisco. Just this year, the US as a whole has seen about 1,000 data breaches. In other words, hackers could set their sights on any company at any time, and more likely than not, they will break through security. Continuing to build security and moving on is the only way to overcome such data breaches.

Verizon can also be compared to other carriers, other than AT&amp;T. T-Mobile has been climbing in the same market. T-Mobile has provided amazing deals, such as the no-contract plans. These plans are just that, without contracts, tying customers to a 2-year contract. The premise is that T-Mobile shows their users that they're services trump other providers and customers can leave without penalty at any time. However, this promotion has caught on and Verizon and AT&amp;T have begun offering similar deals. Therefore, Verizon is still the leader in providers and will continue to be in the future.

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For VZ</strong>

I Know First currently maintains a bullish stance on VZ with signal strength 38.04 and predictability 0.46 for 1 year forecast.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92770 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/snag.jpg" alt="snag" width="429" height="327" /></a>

In the past I Know First was also bullish on VZ. This bullish forecast on VZ was sent to current I Know First subscribers on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/verizon-wireless-stock-forecast-algorithmic-analysis">June 15, 2015</a>, where VZ had a signal of 28.76 and a predictability of 0.31. VZ showed returns of 18% for one year.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Forecast7.jpg" width="727" height="215" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<h3><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
Verizon has a lot in store for consumers in the new year, with acquisition of Yahoo and their soft release of the 5G network. There is much room for growth for these reasons as well as continual release of new and intriguing cell phones that ultimately boost their revenue.

<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" width="70" height="73" />This article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Verizon Stock Analysis</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Verizon (VZ) Stock Analysis</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For VZ</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-verizon-stock-forecast-5g-developments-and-acquisition"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-verizon-stock-forecast-5g-developments-and-acquisition">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>

]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92653</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-02 12:35:33]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-02 10:35:33]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsrar-verizon-stock-forecast-5g-developments-and-acquisition]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="5g"><![CDATA[5g]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="att"><![CDATA[At&amp;t]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="t"><![CDATA[t]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="verizon"><![CDATA[verizon]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="vz"><![CDATA[vz]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wireless"><![CDATA[wireless]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="yahoo"><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[69]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Verizon Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Verizon Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[83]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485193032;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92051;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90395;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92862;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_b46437f8c97f46d496a78b80c643e001]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:0;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[rsar-verizon-stock-analysis-5g-developments-and-acquisition__trashed]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[rsar-verizon-stock-analysis-5g-developments-and-acquisition]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>CBS Stock Analysis: Rewarding Shareholders</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-cbs-stock-analysis-rewarding-shareholders</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 16:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jacob.saphir]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92692</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>  <img class="alignnone wp-image-43664" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-15_18-55-38.png" alt="2016-09-15_18-55-38" width="38" height="61" />  The article was written by Jacob Saphir, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First.</a></em>
<h2>CBS Stock Analysis</h2>
"Mass media provides the essential link between the individual and the demands of the technological society." Jacques Ellul

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92743 size-large" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CBS-Logo-555x246.png" alt="CBS Stock Analysis" width="555" height="246" /></a>

<strong>Summary:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>CBS Corporation background</li>
 	<li>Encouraging data for upcoming 4th quarter earning</li>
 	<li>NFL games will be available on CBS All Access</li>
 	<li>Stock repurchase program may benefit shareholders in the future</li>
</ul>
<strong>Background:</strong>

CBS Corporation, formerly known as Columbia Broadcasting Station, is a worldwide mass media company headquartered in New York, New York.  Once holding an 80% stake in the MLB New York Yankees, the company now operates in 4 segments: Entertainment, Cable Networks, Publishing, and Local Broadcasting.  The entertainment segment earns over 60% in revenue, and 46% of the company's net income as of 2015.  CBS Television Network; CBS Television Studios and CBS Global Distribution Group produces and broadcasts scheduled programmings and sporting events.  The Cable Networks segment operates subscription program services, including digital streaming subscription.  The Publishing segment consists of Simon &amp; Schuster, which publishes printed, digital, and audio books.  32 of New York Times #1 bestsellers of the year 2015 were published by Simon &amp; Schuster.  The Local Broadcasting segment consists of 117 radio stations and 30 television broadcast stations throughout the United States.  Given its operations, what factors are causing the stock price to increase during the year 2016?  CBS has continued to post positive quarterly earnings, signed an important agreement with the NFL, and stock repurchase program.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92877 size-large" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CBS-Building-555x252.png" alt="CBS Stock Analysis" width="555" height="252" /></a>

<strong>Upcoming Quarterly Earnings</strong>

Since reporting the first quarter earnings for the year 2016, CBS has met or exceeded analyst estimate for earnings per share.  In its latest quarterly earnings, CBS surpassed analysts estimation by reporting $1.05 earnings per share, compared to $0.98 earnings per share.  That is over a 7% increase.  Although revenue has been inconsistent since the first quarter report of the year, net income and operating income relative to revenue have been increasing by at least 10%.  This indicates improvement in management efficiency by retaining more in profit given its earned revenue.  Given the company's trend and increase in management efficiency, investors will be anxious to await the 4th quarterly earnings on February 15, 2017.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92872 size-large" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Rising-Chart-555x502.png" alt="CBS Stock Analysis" width="555" height="502" /></a>

<strong>Signing with the National Football League</strong>

On December 1, 2016, CBS signed a crucial deal with the NFL to share games for their digital subscribers in CBS All Access. This took place in early December and could benefit CBS in terms of increasing revenue and subscribers.  As viewers are transitioning to streaming programs, CBS is keeping up with this transition by signing this deal.  On October 2014, CBS became the first mass media company in the United States to offer over the top subscription streaming service.  With the Superbowl approaching, as teams begin the playoffs, viewership is expected to rise.  A rise in viewership could lead to more profit in adverting for the most watched sporting even in the United States.

<img class="wp-image-92880 size-medium aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/NFL-1-300x287.png" width="300" height="287" />

<strong>Stock Repurchase</strong>

The company is in the midst of a $6 billion dollar stock repurchase program.  As of June 30, 2016, it has $1 billion remaining in funds to repurchase common shares.  As CBS continues to complete its stock repurchase plan, investors may see its effect in earnings per share in the long run.  Consequently, when outstanding shares decrease while net income maintains, earnings per share will increase as a result.  Companies reward shareholders either through dividends or stock repurchase.  Although shareholders will see an immediate reward through dividends, stock repurchase may reward shareholders even more in the long term.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92873 size-large" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Boardroom-555x422.png" alt="CBS Stock Analysis" width="555" height="422" /></a>

<strong>Past I Know First Forecast Successes:</strong>

In such as the one dated on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-top-stock-picks-based-on-a-self-learning-algorithm-returns-up-to-43-03-in-3-months">September 26, 2016</a>, the algorithm accurately forecasted a bullish signal for CBS.  Since the forecast's release, the stock increased by over 27% within its given 3 months time span.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-92871 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CBS-Graph-1.png" alt="cbs-graph" width="1099" height="687" /></a>

In another example, the algorithm accurately forecasted a bullish signal for CBS on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-stock-finder-based-on-self-learning-algorithm-over-86-in-2-weeks">September 22, 2016</a>.  The stock increased by over 12 % in its 2 weeks time span.

Below is the latest forecast I Know First algorithm released on January 4, 2017.  If we were to compare the forecast back in <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-top-stock-picks-based-on-a-self-learning-algorithm-returns-up-to-43-03-in-3-months">September 26, 2016</a>, we can see both forecasts rate CBS, Corp. as a buy.  If the previous forecast accurately predicted the stock would increase and it did by over 27%, the latest forecast below could indicate future increase in the stock’s value.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92878 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Forecast-CBS-1-300x200.png" alt="CBS Stock Analysis" width="300" height="200" /></a>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-37141 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/IKForecast_HedgeFunds_26_Sep_2016-90-days-long-until-Dec-26.jpg" alt="CBS Stock Analysis" width="960" height="820" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a class="hasimg" href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" title="" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" alt="" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em>  <img class="alignnone wp-image-43664" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-15_18-55-38.png" alt="2016-09-15_18-55-38" width="38" height="61" />  The article was written by Jacob Saphir, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First.</a></em>
<h2>CBS Stock Analysis</h2>

<strong>Summary:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Encouraging data for upcoming 4th quarter earning</li>
 	<li>NFL games will be available on CBS All Access</li>
 	<li>Stock repurchase program may benefit shareholders in the future</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-cbs-stock-analysis-rewarding-shareholders"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-cbs-stock-analysis-rewarding-shareholders">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92692</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-05 18:07:42]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-05 16:07:42]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-cbs-stock-analysis-rewarding-shareholders]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="cbs"><![CDATA[CBS]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="jacob-saphir"><![CDATA[Jacob Saphir]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="mass-media"><![CDATA[mass media]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="stock-repurchase"><![CDATA[stock repurchase]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[CBS Stock Analysis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[CBS Stock Analysis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[82]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_57fe0d1af3f5c9ee3e04f8baa6e5ab62]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_728c5cf1e07136d4d6e4c590735dc680]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_9508a13cbe0d5b1c22e8b89c244e76cf]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_b0957818e5f73c08ebcd03e87a102377]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485228928;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:43481;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91435;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:50042;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:3;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Allergan Stock Analysis: Renewing Confidence in 2017</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-allergan-stock-analysis-renewing-confidence-in-2017</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 10:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92771</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" width="70" height="73" />This article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Allergan Stock Analysis</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Allergan (AGN) Stock Analysis</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For AGN</li>
</ul>
<strong>Allergan (AGN) Stock Analysis</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92776 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Allergan_Logo.png" alt="allergan_logo" width="704" height="189" /></a>

Allergan plc (AGN), headquartered in Dublin, Ireland, is a bold, global pharmaceutical company and a leader in a new industry model – Growth Pharma. Allergan is focused on developing, manufacturing and commercializing branded pharmaceuticals, devices and biologic products for patients around the world. Allergan markets a portfolio of leading brands and best-in-class products for the central nervous system, eye care, medical aesthetics and dermatology, gastroenterology, women's health, urology and anti-infective therapeutic categories. Allergan is an industry leader in Open Science, the Company’s R&amp;D model, which defines their approach to identifying and developing game-changing ideas and innovation for better patient care. This approach has led to Allergan building one of the broadest development pipelines in the pharmaceutical industry with 70+ mid-to-late stage pipeline programs in development.

AGN price per share currently stands at $210.01 as of December 30, 2016, gaining 1.35% or $2.80 since its previous close on December 29, 2016. AGN, according to the S&amp;P 500, has been one of the worst performing stock in 2016. In 2016, Actavis and Allergen merged seamlessly and Allergan also sold the generics business to Israel's top pharmaceutical company, Teva. With these successful hurdles, the company also had downfalls, leading to its reputation of being one of the worst performing stocks. Firstly, management in 2016 invested their time and effort into transformation of the company, leading to investor confusion which then led to loss of faith by investors. Lastly, in the last few months of the year, consensus on earnings decreased from $17 billion to $15.3 billion. Shares for AGN have also decreased, as there has been a loss of 40% year to date. AGN's Q3 earnings report estimates weren't reached, creating a less than lustrous forecast for the rest of the year.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92778 alignright" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/globuli-medical-bless-you-homeopathy-163186.jpeg" alt="globuli-medical-bless-you-homeopathy-163186" width="354" height="266" /></a>

In 2016, AGN was preparing for its successful future. Selling the generic business to Teva will prove lucrative. AGN is no longer needed for generic because their goal is inevitably become a leading growth pharmaceutical company. The downgrade on estimates was due to an unstable practice that included yearly increase in estimates by 10%. Therefore the estimate downgrade was simply to move it to a more reasonable price.

On December 20, AGN announced that they will also acquire LifeCell, a regenerative medicine company, for $2.9 billion. This will be paid in cash, meaning that the company will not be adding debt. This is a step in the right direction, as 2017 will be the year that AGN will break out of its bad luck in the market. Through the acquisition, AGN will gain "high-quality and durable portfolio of dermal matrix products with Allergan's leading portfolio of medical aesthetics, breast implants and tissue expanders"<em>. </em>These regenerative products will yield immense opportunity to AGN as it will open up markets globally for plastic and general surgery customers. LifeCell assets are estimated to generate about $450 million more revenue in 2016, an approximate increase of 75% in gross margins and 40% operating margins. Apart from the new products it will attain from LifeCell, AGN will also acquire the company's manufacturing capabilities as well as its research and development operations that are located in New Jersey.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92777 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Lifecell_Internation_pvt_ltd.png" alt="lifecell_internation_pvt_ltd" width="443" height="100" /></a>

Possibly due to the positive outlook in 2017, short interest in AGN has dropped 14,879,302 shares to 25,269,718 which equates to a decrease of 37% in just 15 days between 11/30/2016-12/15/2016. This generally means that short sell investors do not see any more potential for the company to decline further, corroborating the new positive forecasting for AGN.

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For AGN</strong>

I Know First currently maintains a bullish stance on AGN with signal strength 108.67 and predictability 0.72 for 1 year forecast.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92775 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/snag-1.jpg" alt="Allergan Stock Analysis" width="405" height="313" /></a>

In the past I Know First was also bullish on AGN. This bullish forecast on AGN was sent to current I Know First subscribers on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/trend-following-based-on-pattern-recognition-return-up-to-55-49-in-3-days">May 15, 2016</a>, where AGN had a signal of 13.27 and a predictability of 0.12. AGN reached 2.64% in returns.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignnone" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/pharm3days.jpg" width="735" height="594" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<strong> Conclusion</strong>

This year will be one of growth for Allergan, all of the changes in the last year that weighed the company down, were just building blocks to achieve bigger and better goals.

<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" width="70" height="73" />This article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Allergan Stock Analysis</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Allergan (AGN) Stock Analysis</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For AGN</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-allergan-stock-analysis-renewing-confidence-in-2017"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-allergan-stock-analysis-renewing-confidence-in-2017">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92771</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-03 12:01:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-03 10:01:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-allergan-stock-analysis-renewing-confidence-in-2017]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="actavis"><![CDATA[actavis]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="agn"><![CDATA[AGN]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="allergan"><![CDATA[allergan]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="pharmaceutical"><![CDATA[pharmaceutical]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="teva"><![CDATA[Teva]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_78736da9e1faa148a18c927192eff1c8]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Allergan Stock Analysis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Allergan Stock Analysis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[83]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485228988;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90544;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90220;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90329;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:2;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Top Performing Stocks of 2016</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-top-performing-stocks-2016</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92784</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Top Performing Stocks of 2016</h2>
Summary
<ul>
 	<li>Top Performing Stocks of 2016</li>
 	<li>I Know First Bullish Forecast for Top Performing Stocks of 2016</li>
</ul>
<strong>Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corp. Class C (AGM)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92794 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/logo.png" alt="logo" width="438" height="51" /></a>

Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corp. is a stockholder-owned, federally chartered corporation. The company provides a secondary market for agricultural real estate and rural housing mortgage loans, rural utilities loans, and loans guaranteed by the United States Department of Agriculture. It combines private capital and public sponsorship to serve a public purpose. The company operates through three segments: Farm and Ranch, USDA Guarantees and Rural Utilities. Federal Agricultural Mortgage was founded in 1987 and is headquartered in Washington, DC.

This past year, AGM steadily increased until it spiked in November of 2016. Around this time, banks began to increase interest rates which were then subsequently announced the following month. This led to AGM's increase in share price.

Past bullish forecast can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-bank-stock-picks-based-on-machine-learning-returns-up-to-93-28-in-1-year">here</a>.

<strong>82% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>Advanced Micro Devices Inc. (AMD)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8692/16980768497_c26b03d7ea_b.jpg" width="421" height="160" /></a>

Over the past year, Advanced Micron Technologies has been making huge strides in the market to expand and recapture market shares in various gaming technology markets. Its recent Q3 2016 reports, ending in September, had shown that revenue had increased over 23% from $1,061 million in Q3 2015 to $1,307 million during the previous quarter. CEO Lisa Su, who took over the struggling firm two years back, has put the firm on a track for a complete turn around. Essentially, the firm had begun to refocusing its operations on what made it great in the past, which was powerful GPU systems and other graphic solution devices. A huge potential tailwind for AMD is the Zen processor unit, set to be released in 2017, which will offer a newly advanced GPU type software.

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-new-technology-can-expand-market-share-increase-bottom-line">AMD Stock Forecast</a>: New Technology Can Expand Market Share &amp; Increase Bottom Line
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-prediction-why-advanced-micro-devices-can-continue-moving-higher">AMD Stock Prediction</a>: Why Advanced Micro Devices Can Continue Moving Higher</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-amd-stock-prediction-getting-10-of-x86-server-processor-market-will-greatly-boost-amds-revenue">AMD Stock Prediction</a>: Getting 10% of x86 Server Processor Market Will Greatly Boost AMD’s Revenue</p>
<strong>309% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp "Freddie Mac" (FMCC)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92793 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Freddie-Mac-Logo.png" alt="freddie-mac-logo" width="380" height="135" /></a>

Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp. provides liquidity, stability and affordability to the U.S. housing market primarily by providing credit guarantee for residential mortgages originated by mortgage lenders and investing in mortgage loans and mortgage-related securities. The company conducts business in the U.S. residential mortgage market and the global securities market under the direction of Conservator, FHFA and under regulatory supervision of FHFA, the SEC, HUD and Treasury. It operates its business through following segments: Single-family Guarantee, Investments and Multifamily. Federal Home Loan Mortgage was founded on July 24, 1970 and is headquartered in McLean, VA.

Just like AGM, FMCC is effected by interest rates and this plays a very big part in why FMCC has increased in the last year.

Quick win on FMCC can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/qw-quick-win-algorithm-fmcc-68-54-last-month">here</a>.

<strong>125.3% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>Freeport-McMoRan Inc. (FCX)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-91487" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Freeport.jpg" alt="fcx stock analysis" width="394" height="197" /></a>

Freeport-McMoRan Inc. (FCX) is a natural resources company with headquarters in Phoenix, Arizona. FCX operates large, long-lived, geographically diverse assets with significant proven and probable reserves of copper, gold, molybdenum, oil and natural gas. FCX is the world’s largest publicly traded copper producer, the world’s largest producer of molybdenum, and a significant gold, oil and natural gas producer.

FCX benefitted from increase in oil prices as well as increase in copper prices, both are main commodities the company deals in. The OPEC deal effected almost all oil companies in a positive light as oil got more expensive. As for copper, President Elect Trump's promise for updates in infrastructure moved copper prices up as well.

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-fcx-stock-analysis-faltering-copper-demand-along-with-poor-fundamentals-creates-a-short-sell-oppurtunity">FCX Stock Analysis</a>: Faltering Copper Demand Along With Poor Fundamentals Creates A Short Sell Oppurtunity

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-fcx-stock-analysis-trump-influences-copper">FCX Stock Analysis</a>: Trump influences Copper

101.37% returns in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>MBT Financial Corp.(MBTF)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92796 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/logo-1.png" alt="logo-1" width="351" height="178" /></a>

MBT Financial Corp. is a bank holding company, which operates through its subsidiary Monroe Bank &amp; Trust. It offers various deposit products which include checking and savings accounts, time deposits, safe deposit facilities, commercial loans, personal loans, real estate mortgage loans, installment loans, IRAs, ATM and night depository facilities, treasury management services, telephone and internet banking, personal trust, employee benefit and investment management services. The company was founded in January 2000 and is headquartered in Monroe, MI.

After Brexit bank stocks went down, they then recovered, increasing share price. Once interest rates went up, all banks began to see an increase in share price and MBTF is no exception.

Past bullish forecast can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-stock-market-outlook-based-on-deep-learning-returns-up-to-65-09-in-1-year">here</a>.

<strong>65.69% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>McDermott International (MDR)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92792 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/McDermott-International-logo.jpg" alt="mcdermott-international-logo" width="377" height="125" /></a>

McDermott International, Inc. is an engineering, procurement, constructions and installation company, which focuses on designing and executing complex offshore oil and gas projects worldwide. It provides EPCI services and delivers fixed and floating production facilities, pipeline installations and subsea systems from concept to commissioning. It operates through the following segments: Americas, Europe, and Africa (AEA); the Middle East (MEA); and Asia (ASA). The company was founded in 1923 and is headquartered in Houston, TX.

As with most oil companies, their stock price grew substantially following the announcement of the OPEC deal.

Previous bullish forecast can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-robo-advisor-based-on-artificial-intelligence-returns-up-to-130-20-in-1-year">here</a>.

<strong>122.59% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>Newmont Mining Corp. (NEM)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92788 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Newmont-Mining-Logo.svg_.png" alt="newmont-mining-logo-svg" width="344" height="130" /></a>

Newmont is one of the world’s leading gold producers, and an industry leader in safety and sustainability. The Company was founded in 1921 and has been publicly traded since 1925. Headquartered in Colorado, Newmont has approximately 28,000 employees and contractors, the majority of whom work at operations in the United States, Australia, New Zealand, Peru, Indonesia and Ghana.

Being that NEM is a leading gold producer, the share price is heavily influenced by the commodities price on the market. In the summer of 2016, gold spiked which then spiked NEM as well. Since the spike, both gold and NEM have gone down in share price but they are still producing great returns for the year.

<strong>84.8% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>NVIDIA Corporation (NVDA)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92786" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/images.png" alt="Top Performing Stocks" width="315" height="158" /></a>

Nvidia is the pioneer of GPU-accelerated computing. They specialize in products and platforms for the large, growing markets of gaming, professional visualization, data center, and automotive, artificial intelligence.

NVDA has released new products throughout the year and have partnered up with huge companies such as Microsoft and Nintendo, thus moving the share price forward immensely. To read about products and partnerships, click the links below.

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/qw-quick-win-by-the-algorithm-nvda-still-climbing-up-over-9-in-3-days">Quick Win by the Algorithm</a>: NVDA Still Climbing, Up Over 9% in 3 Days

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-nvda-stock-analysis-why-nvda-shares-will-continue-to-soar">Nvidia Stock Analysis</a>: Why NVDA Shares Will Continue To Soar

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/nvda-stock-forecast-for-2017">NVDA</a> Stock Forecast for 2017

<strong>229.75%</strong> <strong>returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.<strong>Spectra Energy Corp. (SE)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92789" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Spectra_Energy.svg_.png" alt="spectra_energy-svg" width="335" height="179" /></a>

Spectra Energy Corp (NYSE: SE), a FORTUNE 500 company, is one of North America's leading pipeline and midstream companies. Based in Houston, Texas, the company’s operations in the United States and Canada include approximately 21,000 miles of natural gas and crude oil pipelines; approximately 300 billion cubic feet (Bcf) of natural gas storage; 4.8 million barrels of crude oil storage; as well as natural gas gathering, processing, and local distribution operations. Spectra Energy is the general partner of Spectra Energy Partners (NYSE: SEP), one of the largest pipeline master limited partnerships in the United States and owner of the natural gas and crude oil assets in Spectra Energy’s U.S. portfolio. Spectra Energy also has a 50 percent ownership in DCP Midstream, the largest producer of natural gas liquids and the largest natural gas processor in the United States. Spectra Energy has served North American customers and communities for more than a century.

SE has its hands in many top companies through their portfolio as well as their own successful natural gas an oil pipelines. With increase in usage of natural gas and the increase of oil prices, SE has benefitted greatly.

Bullish Forecast for SE can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-black-box-trading-based-on-deep-learning-returns-up-to-177-45-in-1-year">here</a>.

<strong>66.01% returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>Vale SA Preference Shares (VALE)</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92791 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale_logo.svg_.png" alt="vale_logo-svg" width="391" height="160" /></a>

Vale SA engages in the production and export of iron ore, pellets, manganese, and iron alloys, which are raw materials needed for steelmaking. It operates through the following segments: Ferrous Minerals, Coal, Base Metals, Fertilizers and Others. The Ferrous Minerals segment includes the extraction of iron ore and the production of pellets, manganese ore, iron alloys, and coal, and logistics services. The company was founded on June 1, 1942 and is headquartered in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.

Iron ore prices have gone up in the last year, being that VALE produces and exports iron ore, this has benefitted them. The rise is also attributed to three factors favorable analyst rating and improving financials.

I Know First Review on VALE can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/i-know-first-review-vale-s-a-vale">here</a>.

Quick win on VALE can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/qw-quick-win-by-the-algorithm-vale-is-looking-optimistic">here</a>.

<strong>128.4%</strong> <strong>returns</strong> in a year, beginning January 4, 2016-December 30, 2016.

<strong>I Know First Bullish Forecast for Top Performing Stocks of 2016</strong>

I Know First currently maintains a bullish stance on all 10 stocks with signal strengths and predictability for the 1 year forecast shown below.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-92798" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-03-at-3.57.23-PM.png" alt="screen-shot-2017-01-03-at-3-57-23-pm" width="868" height="259" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<h3></h3>

<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Top Performing Stocks of 2016</h2>
Summary
<ul>
 	<li>Top Performing Stocks of 2016</li>
 	<li>I Know First Bullish Forecast for Top Performing Stocks of 2016</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-top-performing-stocks-2016"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="  https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-top-performing-stocks-2016">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92784</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-03 11:07:20]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-03 09:07:20]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-top-performing-stocks-2016]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="agm"><![CDATA[AGM]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="i-know-first-reviews"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Performance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="amd"><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="fcx"><![CDATA[FCX]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="fmcc"><![CDATA[fmcc]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="mbtf"><![CDATA[MBTF]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="mdr"><![CDATA[MDR]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nem"><![CDATA[nem]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nvda"><![CDATA[NVDA]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="se"><![CDATA[SE]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="vale"><![CDATA[Vale]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[38]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_b8ec85f6a5fd2b6b7f05ed68f340a40e]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_54a18b7792577c6a8eaf643bb316cbf0]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Top Performing Stocks]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Top Performing Stocks]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[77]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1484571270;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92643;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92476;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92771;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:1;s:9:"pinterest";i:1;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>JPM Stock Analysis: JPMorgan Set to Surge in 2017</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-jpm-stock-analysis-jpmorgan-set-to-surge-in-2017</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 09:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92862</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>JPM Stock Analysis</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>JPM Stock Analysis</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For JPM</li>
</ul>
<strong>JPM Stock Analysis</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-92866" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/J_P_Morgan_Chase_Logo_2008_1.svg_.png" alt="j_p_morgan_chase_logo_2008_1-svg" width="2000" height="250" /></a>

JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. (JPM) is a financial holding company, which provides financial and investment banking services. It offers a range of investment banking products and services in all major capital markets, including advising on corporate strategy and structure; capital-raising in equity and debt markets; sophisticated risk management; market-making in cash securities and derivative instruments; and prime brokerage and research. It also offers investment banking, financial services for consumers, small business and commercial banking, financial transaction processing, asset management and private equity. The company operates its business through the following segments: Consumer and Community Banking; Corporate and Investment Bank; Commercial Banking; and Asset Management. The company was founded in 1968 and is headquartered in New York, NY.

JPM is currently dominating in the market where it has risen to $87.23 per share. This price is the highest the stock has ever been since it began public trading in 1983. This is happening even before President Elect Trump is sworn into office. The reason this is important is because of Trump's vow of creating jobs and increasing business potential. Once he is in office, the banks, especially JPM, will benefit heavily. JPM is a great dividend stock as it pays $0.48 per share, per quarter. Each year the dividend is evaluated and since 2009, the dividend has increased 247%. The price target for JPM stock is $91.72, which is only about 5% above the current share price. If JPM reaches the price target, then the company will be worth about $330 billion.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-92865" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-04-at-2.43.12-PM.png" alt="screen-shot-2017-01-04-at-2-43-12-pm" width="320" height="420" /></a>JPM's quarterly report is set to be released on January 13, 2017 and it is expected that earnings price per share will increase $1.40 which is up 3.7% ($0.05) from last years $1.35 per share. Expected profits will be about $5.04 billion if EPS reaches $1.40. There are currently 23 analysts covering JPM with 13 analysts giving JPM a buy rating, 2 giving JPM a sell and 8 rate the stock as hold.

The 2009 recession caused by the 2008 housing crash completely decimated banks and businesses, however; JPM overcame the mound of issues and even came out stronger. The bank is much better positioned in the market than it ever has been, using the downfalls in 2009 to build a stronger foundation on which to grow. Since 2008, JPM has reduced their net loss provision, also known as the loan loss provision. This factor plays a large roll in JPM's balance sheet as it is a large sum of money put aside by the bank to guard against potential loan loss and default on loans. This means that whatever money they had to keep aside can now be used to increase business prospects, which will ultimately grow the company further. This has also allowed JPM to begin share buybacks and in 2016 JPM board members approved a $10.6 billion buyback.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92867 alignright" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/bank-sunrise.jpg" alt="bank-sunrise" width="357" height="238" /></a>

In 2017, JPMorgan is estimated to top any expectations because of Trump as briefly discussed above. The reason being that the business environment when he comes into office, will be much better. Not only will this affect how JPM is run, but also how other businesses run, ultimately working in favor of banks in general. Banks make up a large portion of loan opportunities for businesses, if smaller, or even larger, businesses turn to JPM for their business dealings, including loans, then that will put JPM on a positive course for years to come.

Because JPM is a bank, most of its dealing is on loans, which includes interest rates. Currently, the interest rates have gone up, which will inevitably strengthen JPM because it creates a larger profit margin for the bank, thus benefitting their bottom line. This may not be favorable for consumers, but for financial institutions like JPM, it will benefit immensely. More information about the increase in interest rates can be found <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-bac-stock-forecast-bank-of-america-benefits-from-increase-in-interest-rates">here</a>.

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For JPM</strong>

I Know First currently maintains a bullish stance on JPM with signal strength 143.34 and predictability 0.63 for 1 year forecast.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="size-full wp-image-92868 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/snag-2.jpg" alt="snag" width="440" height="330" /></a>

In the past I Know First was also bullish on JPM. This bullish forecast on JPM was sent to current I Know First subscribers on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/top-stock-research-an-average-return-of-15-69-in-1-year">August 22, 2014</a>, where JPM had a signal of 4.23 and a predictability of 0.46. JPM showed returns of 11.61% for one year.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignnone" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/IKForecast_Banks.jpg" width="749" height="420" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<strong> Conclusion</strong>

JPMorgan will be a winner in 2017 and right now would be the time to buy the stock as it is at its low for the incoming year based on predictability and the increase in interest rates. In general, JPM is a solid stock to have in a portfolio.

<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>JPM Stock Analysis</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>JPM Stock Analysis</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithm Bullish Forecast For JPM</li>
</ul>


<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-jpm-stock-analysis-jpmorgan-set-to-surge-in-2017"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="  https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-top-performing-stocks-2016">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92862</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-05 11:33:19]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-05 09:33:19]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-jpm-stock-analysis-jpmorgan-set-to-surge-in-2017]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="bac"><![CDATA[BAC]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="bank"><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="chase"><![CDATA[chase]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="interest-rate"><![CDATA[interest rate]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="jpm"><![CDATA[JPM]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="jpmorgan"><![CDATA[jpmorgan]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="trump"><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[69]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[JPM Stock Analysis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[JPM Stock Analysis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[77]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_bee43e5db9c60f26b87551f9e8c3be29]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485280560;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90544;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90395;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92476;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:3;s:9:"pinterest";i:1;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>AI Hedge Fund: Hedge Funds With Machine Learning Capabilities</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-hedge-funds-with-machine-learning-capabilities</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 09:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92914</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>AI Hedge Fund</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>AI Hedge Fund and Machine Learning</li>
 	<li>I Know First and Hedge Funds</li>
</ul>
<strong>AI Hedge Fund and Machine Learning</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92976 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/man.png" alt="man" width="200" height="224" /></a>

Hedge funds using artificial intelligence are becoming a staple. Consumers want to know that their investment is safe and secure, so they have turned to hedge funds that utilize AI. Tim Wong, the chairman of AHL and Man Group Asia has been successful using AI in hedge funds. However, he doesn't plan on getting rid of employees altogether. Instead he plans on continually employing professionals because of possible dangers that would come into play if the AI system is left unchecked. Even so, "famous hedge fund managers are being replaced by super computers with complex algorithms to watch and predict the market in order to make better bids. Rather than these managers working with hedge funds, PhD holders in mathematics are developing new ways to look at data through mathematical equations, essentially replacing the hedge fund manager" <em>Retrieved from <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-artificial-intelligence-taking-over-hedge-fund-markets">AI Hedge Fund</a>.</em>

AI, though, isn't enough in the financial industry. Machine learning, which is part of AI, is a way for machines to learn from their data and grow, just like humans learn. Specifically, machine learning is "a method of data analysis that automates analytical model building. Using algorithms that iteratively learn from data, machine learning allows computers to find hidden insights without being explicitly programmed where to look" (<em>Retrieved from <a href="http://www.sas.com/en_us/insights/analytics/machine-learning.html">SAS</a>). <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92975 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/pexels-photo-159888.jpeg" alt="pexels-photo-159888" width="433" height="324" /></a></em>

Hedge funds have moved into the AI sector because with such large amounts of data in the market, machines can better process it as well as find patterns within the market at a much quicker rate. And at this day in age, we produce massive amounts of data on a daily basis, much more than we ever used to in the past. This is where AI excels and humans do not. While humans can consume large amounts of data and can adequately detect patterns from the given data, there is a limit. Humans can only work through data for certain periods and at a certain rate. Because humans are living beings, they get distracted, thus further limiting the pace that they can analyze data. AI can incorporate even the smallest amounts of data, digest it, and come up with patterns in a speed that no man can compete with. At this point, it is a given that financial markets should be analyzed for patterns by machines rather than humans. It's cost-effective, quick, and human error is effectively eliminated. However, as briefly mentioned above, humans aren't being completely erased from the equation. Wong continues employing financial professionals in order to manage risk. Wong stated that his team meets weekly in order to discuss possible problems with the program and how they would react if that were to happen, effectively creating emergency plans for any problem (<em>Retrieved from <a href="http://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/2058851/hedge-funds-embrace-machine-learning-humans-are-still">SCMP</a>)</em>.

Though the system incorporates AI machine learning, humans play an important role because it isn't completely self-sufficient as of yet. Again, there may be issues that arise that require a human to fix as the machine may not realize that their pattern detection has gone of course. There are two types of machine learning within AI, supervised and unsupervised learning. In this case, AHL and Man Group Asia's algorithm is supervised, which at this point in time, is the most frequently used. A supervised system is where a human must input certain variables as well as the output on the variables, which then teaches the algorithm to map the input and output functions. In essence, the human is teaching the algorithm how to function with the data set that they are give. Very much like a human learning from a human teacher.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-92977 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/startup-photos.jpg" alt="startup-photos" width="426" height="284" /></a>

Conversely, the unsupervised machine learning entails an input data set but the human does not give the algorithm an output. The idea is that the algorithm will take the input and evaluate the structure which then leads the algorithm to learn more about the type of data involved. Unsupervised algorithmic data sets have no correct answer and there is no "teacher" involved. It is entirely up to the algorithm to digest the data and draw conclusions based on the data.

While Wong begins to use algorithmic models for the company's hedge fund, I Know First has already created an algorithm that not only incorporates machine learning, but also incorporates neural networks that evolve in time. Although I Know First doesn't manage its own hedge fund, the company does follow top stocks that are included in top hedge fund portfolios.
<p class="p1"><strong>I Know First and Hedge Funds</strong></p>
<p class="p1">I Know First predicts a growing universe of over 3000 securities for the short, medium and long term horizons daily by applying Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning techniques to search for patterns and relationships in large sets of historical stock market data.</p>
<p class="p1">Through it’s self-learning ability and flexible multi-layered neural networks structure, the algorithm is able to learn from, adapt to and evolve together with continuously changing markets. It offers an independent, objective and unique perspective on the financial markets and doesn’t rely on any human derived assumptions or traditional theories and models that often do not hold (any more).</p>
The results of intense learning and prediction cycles are aggregated into two indicators per time frame: signal and predictability. While predictability indicator helps to identify and focus on the most predictable assets, the signal is used to define and rank the trades and is related to the magnitude of expected return.

The applications of the algorithmic AI-based forecasts are multi-fold.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-92920 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/process.jpg" alt="AI Hedge Fund" width="1011" height="389" /></a>

The scalability of the algorithmic predictive system allows I Know First to offer custom forecasting solutions to hedge funds and other financial institutions, so they can identify the best opportunities as discovered by the self-learning algorithm within the investment universe of their interest. Further, the solution can be used as a decision support system in form of an algorithmic screen integrated into client’s investment process in order to confirm or reject investment ideas before the execution.

Moreover, I Know First develops and back-tests systematic trading strategies which are used in partnerships with hedge funds and other asset managing entities. These strategies are rules-based and utilize algorithmic forecasting indicators mentioned above in order to rank and select the trades as well as time the execution. The type of strategies varies, including mean-reversion logic and more trend focused approaches, all generating high positive alpha while keeping beta in the  0.3-0.8 range, yielding overall high risk-adjusted returns. The strategies can be used in partnership with I Know First to launch hedge funds, mutual funds or other investment vehicles.

<img src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Screen-Shot-2016-11-08-at-10.44.49-AM.png" alt="screen-shot-2016-11-08-at-10-44-49-am" />

For further information, please review related articles:
<ul>
 	<li>
<p class="postitle"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/algar-stock-predictions-daily-stock-selection-based-on-a-self-learning-algorithm-january-november-2016">Stock Predictions: Daily Stock Selection Based On a Self-Learning Algorithm January-November 2016</a></p>
</li>
 	<li>
<p class="postitle"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/analysis-influence-know-first-signal-predictability-indicators-trade-selection">Stock Filtering by the I Know First Signal and Predictability Indicators</a></p>
</li>
 	<li>
<p class="postitle"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/day-trading-strategy">Day Trading Strategy: An In-depth Analysis of Realistic Back-Tests</a></p>
</li>
 	<li>
<p class="postitle"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/algar_short-term-trading-summary-of-realistic-backtests-based-on-daily-stock-selection">Short-term Trading: Summary of Realistic Backtests based on Daily Stock Selection</a></p>
</li>
 	<li>
<p class="postitle"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-bridgewater-using-ai-to-increase-profits-and-productivity">AI Hedge Fund: Bridgewater Using AI to Increase Profits and Productivity</a></p>
</li>
 	<li><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-artificial-intelligence-taking-over-hedge-fund-markets">AI Hedge Fund: Artificial Intelligence Taking over Hedge Fund Markets</a></li>
</ul>
Or contact I Know First at:
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Research@IKnowFirst.com</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>AI Hedge Fund</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>AI Hedge Fund and Machine Learning</li>
 	<li>I Know First and Hedge Funds</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-hedge-funds-with-machine-learning-capabilities"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-hedge-funds-with-machine-learning-capabilities">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92914</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-10 11:59:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-10 09:59:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-ai-hedge-fund-hedge-funds-with-machine-learning-capabilities]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ai"><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="hedge-fund"><![CDATA[Hedge Fund]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="machine-learning"><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[69]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:32:"f5b9441c1cff8609eb710ebd49a6e723";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485196931;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91209;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:93112;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92538;}}}s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485225760;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91209;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:93112;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92538;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[AI Hedge Fund]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[AI Hedge Fund]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[72]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:3;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Tesla Stock Forecast for 2017</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-tesla-stock-forecast-for-2017</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 16:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92978</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Tesla Stock Forecast</h2>
<p class="quoteText"><em>“Let the future tell the truth, and evaluate each one according to his work and accomplishments. The present is theirs; the future, for which I have really worked, is mine” ― Nikola Tesla</em></p>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Tesla Forecast for 2017</li>
 	<li>Performance and earnings review</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For TSLA</li>
</ul>
<strong>Tesla Forecast for 2017</strong>
<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92985 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/tesla.png" alt="tesla forecast" width="300" height="259" /></a>

Tesla Motors, Inc. designs, develops, manufactures, and sells electric vehicles and stationary energy storage products in the United States, China, Norway, and internationally. It primarily offers sedans and sport utility vehicles. The company also offers electric vehicle powertrain components and systems to other manufacturers. It sells its products through a network of Tesla stores and galleries, as well as through Internet. In addition, the company designs, manufactures, installs, monitors, maintains, leases, and sells solar energy systems to government, residential, and commercial customers; and sells electricity generated by solar energy systems to customers. Tesla Motors, Inc. was founded in 2003 and is headquartered in Palo Alto, California.

Last year, Tesla (TSLA) didn't do as well as you would think, being that Tesla is a household name when referring to the future of the electric vehicle. The reason it performed so poorly was because of an 11% drop in February of 2016 due to a decrease in gas prices as well as doubtful investors stemming from Tesla's long-term goals rather than immediate growth. At that point, the share price dropped from $223.41 on January 4, 2016 to $143.67 on February 10, 2016. Since this drop in share price, TSLA has been quite volatile as it shot up in the next two months to over $265 per share and back down below $200 per share in early September. However, TSLA closed the year at $213.69 and has been steadily going up since. TSLA now stands at $229.01 before open on January 9, 2017. This is partially due to the Q3 earnings Tesla released in October. Their Q3 was only their second quarter where the company came out profitable. They did so well in Q3 that it exceeded any expectations and predictions. In Q3, Tesla earned $0.71 per share on $2.3 billion in revenue. Expected performance by analysts for Tesla was a loss of $0.54 on a $1.98 billion revenue. Their increase in revenue was said to be because of "new product launches, increased store efficiency, and new store openings as some of the major factors driving third-quarter results"<em> Retrieved from <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2016/10/26/tesla-reports-third-quarter-earnings.html">CNBC</a>. </em>A few weeks before the Q3 report was released, Tesla announced that they reached record deliveries and production numbers on vehicles that jumped 70% on deliveries and 37% on production from Q2. By the end of September of 2016, Tesla reported $3.1 billion in liquidity, investing $248 million in production, construction and infrastructure growth from the previous quarter. Also in Q3, Tesla paid off $600 million in debt which offered the company $300 million in vehicle leasing programs.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class=" wp-image-92986 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/tesla-model-3-speed-elon-musk-price.jpg" alt="tesla-model-3-speed-elon-musk-price" width="652" height="375" /></a>This year, TSLA will either plummet or succeed with their new Tesla Model 3. The new model will be released later this year and will be the most affordable model that the company has ever released. The new model will be priced at $35,000 including tax incentives. The fact that Tesla is releasing a new model that is cost efficient for the regular consumer shows that the company has grown and adapted from its exorbitant previous prices on older models.

This new model will be released at the perfect time as the OPEC deal, cutting oil production all over the world, will increase gas prices tremendously at a time when people are already trying to turn away from gas guzzling vehicles. This creates the perfect storm for the Model 3 as consumers get rid of their older gas vehicles and move toward the affordable and highly sought after electric Tesla's.

While all of that may sound promising, there are drawbacks. Tesla has had a hard time producing enough units on time, which will put a damper on the expected sales of the cars. Also, the $35,000 price tag may not be feasible and therefore the company may not be able to actually maintain it. Additionally, the car is being released among the shift in power in the United States, with new leadership being less than favorable toward green energy. However, these factors may not be enough to put a damper on Tesla's growth this year.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-93024" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/22237945806_c54e65cdf1_b.jpg" alt="22237945806_c54e65cdf1_b" width="375" height="281" /></a>

Another new release this year is their autopilot software. Released on Mondy was the software enabling autopilot to 1,000 Tesla owners. The rest of the new Tesla's will also have the software but it will be not be enabled until the end of the week if the test run on the 1,000 vehicles is a success. New features that the software update will brandish include enhancements on radar sensors that will allow the system to see through rain, fog, dust, and will be able to detect cars in front of it, there are also 12 ultrasonic sensors that can detect hard or soft objects at twice the distance as previously. Also, Tesla will be using <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/nvda-stock-forecast-for-2017">Nvidia's</a> Titan <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-nvidia-stock-analysis-teslas-autonomous-car-ambition-is-a-long-term-tailwind-for-nvidia">GPU</a> which will offer users 40 times more computing power compared to the old system. The autopilot system will also match speeds of traffic around the vehicle, change lanes without driver interference, merge onto the freeway, and it will be able to park itself.

Tesla and SolarCity have effectively merged as well, and now that they have, Tesla has partnered with Panasonic in order to manufacture photovoltaic or PV cells. These cells will be used in order to make solar panel roof tiles, rather than the more common panels that are generally seen on top of roofs or in solar farms.

Tesla is a company that many only dream to become, but why are they so successful at what they do? Tesla's competitive advantages are unmatched in the electric vehicle sector and now, due to the solar tiles they will be producing with Panasonic, they are creating a massive upgrade in the solar panel industry. Tesla has many other advantages that position the company way above the rest, such as their batteries, abundance of their supercharging stations, software that is extremely advanced compared to the competition, an amazing reputation in the community. Tesla's batteries are not only cheaper to produce, but they are also better than the more expensive batteries in other electric vehicles. Not only is it better, it continues to be better than the rest as Tesla continually makes upgrades to their existing battery. Along with the battery, comes charging stations. Tesla doesn't just have charging stations, they have extremely quick supercharging stations that don't cost money to use because the price of the electricity is priced into the car. Another advantage, Tesla's software, is updated as often as your phone or tablet. The software is also being produced by<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/nvda-stock-forecast-for-2017"> Nvidia</a>, one of the top GPU companies that utilize advanced artificial intelligence. And lastly, Tesla's reputation completely disassembles any competitors. The company aims to make their customers happy as well as comfortable. If you've ever noticed, Tesla's stores are located within malls in a showroom fashion. It is not a car lot and there aren't any car salesman pestering customers. It's a relaxed environment that can be compared to shopping for clothing. In this sense, Tesla is the perfect car nondealership.

<strong>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For TSLA</strong>

I Know First currently maintains a bullish stance on TSLA with signal strength 46.43 and predictability 0.65 for the 1-year forecast.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93025" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/tesla-1.png" alt="tesla" width="339" height="262" /></a>

In the past I Know First was also bullish on TSLA. This bullish forecast on TSLA was sent to current I Know First subscribers on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-tech-stock-forecast-based-on-predictive-analytics-returns-up-to-38-17-in-7-days">January 1, 2016</a>, where TSLA had a signal of 25.00 and a predictability of 0.18. TSLA showed returns of 8.23% for one year.

<img src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/IKForecast_top_10_Tech_02_Jan_2017-7-days-long-until-Jan-9.jpg" alt="tech stock forecast" />

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<strong> Conclusion</strong>

Tesla may not have done its best last year, but this year is a new beginning with promising possibilities. The car will be more affordable for the average consumer, driving customers to buy the new model, and the new autopilot feature will intrigue many new buyers. This year will be the year that Tesla moves forward.

<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Tesla Forecast for 2017</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Tesla Forecast for 2017</li>
 	<li>Performance and earnings review</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For TSLA</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-tesla-stock-forecast-for-2017"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-tesla-stock-forecast-for-2017">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92978</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-11 18:51:32]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-11 16:51:32]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsrar-tesla-stock-forecast-for-2017]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="autopilot"><![CDATA[autopilot]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="electric"><![CDATA[electric]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="model-3"><![CDATA[Model 3]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nvda"><![CDATA[NVDA]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nvidia"><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tesla"><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tsla"><![CDATA[TSLA]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tesla Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tesla Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485255813;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91067;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90664;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:43958;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:2;s:9:"pinterest";i:1;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>AMD Stock Forecast: Defying Critics</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-defying-critics</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jacob.saphir]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=92988</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<em>  <img class="alignnone wp-image-43664" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-15_18-55-38.png" alt="2016-09-15_18-55-38" width="38" height="61" />  The article was written by Jacob Saphir, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First.</a></em>
<h2>AMD Stock Forecast</h2>
"Competition is not only the basis of protection to the consumer, but is the incentive to progress." Herbert Hoover

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93039 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/AMD-1.png" alt="AMD Stock Analysis" width="736" height="216" /></a>

<strong>Summary:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>AMD continues its positive trend</li>
 	<li>Encouraging key statistic</li>
 	<li>Latest products could result in increasing market share</li>
 	<li>Upbeat anticipation for 4th quarter earnings</li>
</ul>
<strong>Encouraging Key Statistic:</strong>

AMD is defying its critics and proving to the high tech world that the processing and GPU market is not reserved only for Intel and NVIDIA.  As written in a previous I Know First article, under CEO Lisa Su's leadership, she has <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-new-technology-can-expand-market-share-increase-bottom-line">reorganized the company</a>. AMD was among the top stock performers for the year 2016.  A stock yielding over 370% in one year is a company worth looking into.  Because we are eager to learn what to expect in the future.

Some may have missed the opportunity to invest in AMD earlier in the year 2016.  Although the stock rose exponentially, a key ratio, Price to Sales (P/S) may tell otherwise.  Perhaps skeptics still believe the stock is not a bargain as it was before.  However, if we were to compare this key statistics towards other semi-conductor firms, AMD settles at P/S of 2.22.  While, the industry as a whole is higher with a P/S of 3.88.  As a result, AMD is trading with a P/S ratio 42% less than the industry.  Some may interpret this as a bargain.  In the past, the company's P/S ratio was as high as 3.8 during the highs of 2000 and 3.2 during the highs of 2006.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93171 size-large" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/State-555x370.png" alt="AMD Stock Analysis" width="555" height="370" /></a>

<strong>CES 2017 and Ryzen</strong>

Eager to begin the year with excitement, AMD debuted their much anticipated Graphics Processing Unit (GPU), Ryzen + Vega, at the Consumer Electronic Show (CES) 2017 in Las Vegas, Nevada.  With over 100,000 in attendance, AMD showcased its latest products and how Ryzen is applicable to its target market in virtual reality, e-sports, and PC gaming.  According to <a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/4035767-amd-ryzen-may-impact-processor-market-boost-long-term-share-price">seekingalpha.com</a>, the virtual reality PC demand is projected to grow tenfold by 2020 and the PC gaming to grow 35% by 2020.

As of January 8, 2017, although AMD's market share of global processors is significantly less than Intel's, its new processors will pose could pose a challenge.  If the capabilities for its newest processors are correct, this could mean Intel will face stiff competition in the high end processor market, it dominates.  Such a threat could force data center companies to leverage against Intel and fight for lower pricing.  Lower pricing could not only impact Intel's future profit margin, but also increase AMD's market share and revenue stream.  In addition, NVIDIA may also face stiff competition from AMD for its GPU's.  Consequently, NVIDIA could see a decline in market share.  It is becoming evident, as written in a previous I Know First <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-amd-stock-analysis-amd-regaining-market-share">article</a>.  AMD has signed crucial agreements to become GPU suppliers to Google and Alibaba.  Therefore, AMD has room to grow.
<p class="p p5"><a href="http://iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-92990" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CES.png" alt="AMD Stock Analysis" width="600" height="388" /></a></p>
<strong>Upcoming 4th Quarter Earnings:</strong>

AMD will report its 4th quarter earnings for the year 2016 on January 17, 2017.  Since releasing its first quarterly earnings on March 21st, 2016, AMD has surpassed analysts' estimation.  In its latest quarterly earnings released on October 20, 2016, AMD reported a positive earnings per share of $0.03.  Marking it the first time AMD reported a positive earnings for the year.  Given its improved financial situation since CEO Lisa Su took assumed leadership and its positive debut of its latest products, investors will be anxious to see how these upbeat news will translate to earnings reported for next week.  Can AMD continue the trend, post a positive earnings per share, and surpass analysts' expectation?

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93108" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Calender.png" alt="AMD Stock Analysis" width="300" height="401" /></a>

<strong>Past I Know First Forecast Successes:</strong>

In such as the one dated on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/amd-stock-swot-analysis-optimistic-outlook-on-amd-in-2016">March 20, 2016</a>, the algorithm accurately forecasted a bullish signal for AMD.  Since the forecast's release, the stock increased by over 290% within its given 1 year forecast.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93100 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/AMD-Chart-1.png" alt="AMD Stock Analysis" width="1103" height="699" /></a>

In another example, the algorithm accurately forecasted a bullish signal for AMD on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-prediction-why-advanced-micro-devices-can-continue-moving-higher">December 4, 2016</a>.  The stock increased by 34 % in 1 month.

Below is the latest forecast I Know First algorithm released on January 10, 2017.  If we were to compare the forecast back in <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/amd-stock-swot-analysis-optimistic-outlook-on-amd-in-2016">March 20, 2016</a>, we can see both forecasts rate AMD as a buy.  If the previous forecast accurately predicted the stock would increase and it did by over 290%, the latest forecast below could indicate future increase in the stock’s value.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93040 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/AMD-Heat-300x202.png" alt="AMD Stock Analysis" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm. This allows users to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a class="hasimg" href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" title="" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" alt="" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em>  <img class="alignnone wp-image-43664" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-15_18-55-38.png" alt="2016-09-15_18-55-38" width="38" height="61" />  The article was written by Jacob Saphir, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First.</a></em>
<h2>AMD Stock Forecast</h2>

<strong>Summary:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>AMD continues its positive trend</li>
 	<li>Encouraging Key Statistic</li>
 	<li>Latest products could result in increasing market share</li>
 	<li>Upbeat anticipation for 4th quarter earnings</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-defying-critics"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-defying-critics">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92988</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-12 19:20:01]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-12 17:20:01]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-amd-stock-forecast-defying-critics]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="i-know-first-reviews"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Performance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="amd"><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ces"><![CDATA[ces]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ces-2017"><![CDATA[ces 2017]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="gpu"><![CDATA[GPU]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="intel"><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="jacob-saphir"><![CDATA[Jacob Saphir]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nvidia"><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="processor"><![CDATA[processor]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[66]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1976]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_97d215c0e5013b88b925454ada9cdf9c]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="7QTVu2VzEp" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-new-technology-can-expand-market-share-increase-bottom-line">AMD Stock Forecast: New Technology Can Expand Market Share &#038; Increase Bottom Line</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-amd-stock-forecast-new-technology-can-expand-market-share-increase-bottom-line/embed#?secret=7QTVu2VzEp" data-secret="7QTVu2VzEp" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;AMD Stock Forecast: New Technology Can Expand Market Share &#038; Increase Bottom Line&#8221; &#8212; Stock Forecast Based On a Predictive Algorithm | I Know First  |" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_97d215c0e5013b88b925454ada9cdf9c]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484063582]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_ba07918a4e1a99c016a6f6b4e4230156]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="kH7byMxPnV" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-amd-stock-analysis-amd-regaining-market-share">AMD Stock Analysis: AMD Regaining Market Share</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-amd-stock-analysis-amd-regaining-market-share/embed#?secret=kH7byMxPnV" data-secret="kH7byMxPnV" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;AMD Stock Analysis: AMD Regaining Market Share&#8221; &#8212; Stock Forecast Based On a Predictive Algorithm | I Know First  |" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_ba07918a4e1a99c016a6f6b4e4230156]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484063761]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[AMD Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[AMD Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[73]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485340341;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91435;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92411;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:50848;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_7dbbdf81706a5bde61dff01ca5f44b70]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_c7c83f53ea754b6c0a42bcd9b9912faf]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_5a3c1c463527ab7a8dcf3f24266ca05c]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_98c6bb627eec55d5d528773741a112ae]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:1;s:9:"pinterest";i:1;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Netflix Stock Forecast for 2017</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-netflix-stock-forecast-for-2017</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 08:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=93054</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Netflix Stock Forecast for 2017</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Netflix Stock Forecast for 2017</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For Netflix</li>
</ul>
<strong>Netflix Stock Forecast for 2017</strong>
<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="wp-image-93096 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/6126059318_fa4f25535d_b.jpg" alt="6126059318_fa4f25535d_b" width="447" height="296" /></a>

Netflix Inc is an Internet television network with over 86 million members in over 190 countries enjoying more than 125 million hours of television (TV) shows and movies per day, including original series, documentaries and feature films. Members can watch as much as they want, anytime, anywhere, on nearly any Internet-connected screen.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-93094" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Capture.png" alt="capture" width="304" height="382" /></a>

Analysts aren't looking favorably at NFLX currently. Wedbush and Jeffries rated NFLX as "underperform" while Piper Jaffray rated it "overweight," 7 other analysts rated the stock as "sell," and 16 analysts have rated NFLX as a "hold." Bank of America and Pivotal Research were the only companies to rate NFLX as a "buy." Price targets on the stock range from $60.00 per share to $155.00 per share, where the actual share price at close on January 10, 2017 is $129.89. These negative ratings on NFLX shouldn't entirely come as a surprise as the stock has seen a 42-week low of $79.95 and a high of $129.29, with a market cap at about $54 billion and a P/E ratio of 339.43.

However, NFLX hasn't been doing terrible in the last year. NFLX last quarterly earnings were released on Monday, October 17, 2016. EPS growth actually exceeded expectations which were at $0.06 and the stock's actual EPS was $0.12 for the quarter. Revenue during the quarter equaled $2.29 billion as opposed to estimated $2.28 billion. Year-over-year, revenue increased 31.7%. On January 18, 2017, NFLX will be releasing it's Q4 earnings, so we will soon have an idea of which way the stock is moving.

Netflix has been investing on their original content to gain a competitive advantage. The companies goal is to boast 50% of their overall content as their Netflix originals. This investment makes it so that Netflix will have exclusive content that can only be viewed on their platform, driving consumers straight to them to watch certain shows and movies. Competition within video streaming platforms has turned to original content. There is very little that differentiates the companies, so their content is a way to make them look more attractive. The race to the top will simply be based on the popularity of the shows that are provided on each platform.

On another note, there are rumors of possible acquisition on Netflix. Facebook and Disney are possible buyers for Netflix. Facebook though, is a less plausible buyer as the discussion about the buy is just rumors. Disney, however; has had this rumor continuing since December and there are actual outlines as to why the sale may be beneficial for both parties.

Disney would benefit by purchasing Netflix because their content, as well as newer acquired content from Marvel, Pixar and Lucas Films, would have a new, refreshing distribution platform. Also, because Netflix is an international platform, Disney would be able to quickly and easily grow into the global market, even further than it already has. Surprisingly, 45% of Netflix subscribers are international consumers. This could open up new doors for Disney <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="size-full wp-image-93097 alignright" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/download-1.png" alt="download" width="350" height="144" /></a>internationally as their sales outside of the US are only 27% of total revenue, barring Disney theme park sales around the world.
Disney also boasts 90 million subscribers for ESPN and ESPN2, which could be integrated into Netflix. This, however, may not be a benefit. If ESPN and ESPN2 become part of Netflix, subscription fees may go up. While for sports fans, this isn't a huge problem, it is for the rest of Netflix subscribers when there is competition at a lower rate such as Amazon Video and Hulu. Although there is content on Netflix that subscribers are unable to receive on other platforms, it's a small loss compared to having to pay extra for services that are unwanted. All in all, it doesn't make financial sense to acquire Netflix for Disney as the cost would run them around $65 billion which is more than a third of the market cap on Disney stock.

<strong>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For NFLX</strong>

I Know First currently maintains a bullish stance on NFLX with signal strength of 111.02 and predictability 0.42 for the 1-year forecast.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="size-full wp-image-93095 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/nflx.png" alt="nflx" width="431" height="355" /></a>

In the past I Know First was also bullish on NFLX. This bullish forecast on NFLX was sent to current I Know First subscribers on <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-quant-trading-based-on-deep-learning-returns-up-to-26-24-in-14-days">October 12, 2016,</a> where NFLX had a signal of 23.63 and a predictability of 0.18. NFLX showed returns of 26.24% in the 14 day period.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/IKForecast_OPTIONS_Top10_12_Oct_2016-14-days-long-until-October-26.jpg" alt="Quant Trading" width="822" height="684" /></a>

For more information on past performance, click <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-netflix-stock-analysis-bullish-view-of-netflix">here</a>.

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<strong> Conclusion</strong>

No matter what happens, NFLX will continue growing its user base as it grows its own original content. Hulu and Amazon are competitors but Netflix continues to dominate the video streaming sector.

<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Netflix Stock Forecast for 2017</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Netflix Stock Forecast for 2017</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For Netflix</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-netflix-stock-forecast-for-2017"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-netflix-stock-forecast-for-2017">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93054</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-11 10:33:24]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-11 08:33:24]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-netflix-stock-forecast-for-2017]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="acquisition"><![CDATA[acquisition]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="disney"><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="facebook"><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="netflix"><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nflx"><![CDATA[NFLX]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Netflix Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Netflix Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_149f03140777862e267b8895cb088379]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="c3OxBesE4x" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="https://investorplace.com/2017/01/disney-dis-stock-buy-netflix-nflx-stock-should-shouldnt/">Why Walt Disney Co (DIS) Should Buy Netflix, Inc. (NFLX) (And Why It Shouldn&#8217;t)</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://investorplace.com/2017/01/disney-dis-stock-buy-netflix-nflx-stock-should-shouldnt/embed/#?secret=c3OxBesE4x" data-secret="c3OxBesE4x" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;Why Walt Disney Co (DIS) Should Buy Netflix, Inc. (NFLX) (And Why It Shouldn&#8217;t)&#8221; &#8212; InvestorPlace" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_149f03140777862e267b8895cb088379]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484125802]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_f3e9006162e007291e29bb6920bc1b66]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="xSkEmMiSsG" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="http://cnafinance.com/netflix-nflx-stock-gaining-on-acquisition-hopes/13183">Netflix (NFLX) Stock: Gaining On Acquisition Hopes</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="http://cnafinance.com/netflix-nflx-stock-gaining-on-acquisition-hopes/13183/embed#?secret=xSkEmMiSsG" data-secret="xSkEmMiSsG" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;Netflix (NFLX) Stock: Gaining On Acquisition Hopes&#8221; &#8212; CNA Finance" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_f3e9006162e007291e29bb6920bc1b66]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484125818]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_908dcc86d240d859badb264bf9326688]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="zyXvdClqfU" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="http://cnafinance.com/netflix-nflx-stock-gaining-on-acquisition-hopes/13183">Netflix (NFLX) Stock: Gaining On Acquisition Hopes</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="http://cnafinance.com/netflix-nflx-stock-gaining-on-acquisition-hopes/13183/embed#?secret=zyXvdClqfU" data-secret="zyXvdClqfU" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;Netflix (NFLX) Stock: Gaining On Acquisition Hopes&#8221; &#8212; CNA Finance" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_908dcc86d240d859badb264bf9326688]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484125830]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_b589ec8c1e584c10b2331fb184d9949c]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="GHr3AvTz7l" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="http://investorplace.com/2017/01/disney-dis-stock-buy-netflix-nflx-stock-should-shouldnt/">Why Walt Disney Co (DIS) Should Buy Netflix, Inc. (NFLX) (And Why It Shouldn&#8217;t)</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="http://investorplace.com/2017/01/disney-dis-stock-buy-netflix-nflx-stock-should-shouldnt/embed/#?secret=GHr3AvTz7l" data-secret="GHr3AvTz7l" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;Why Walt Disney Co (DIS) Should Buy Netflix, Inc. (NFLX) (And Why It Shouldn&#8217;t)&#8221; &#8212; InvestorPlace" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_b589ec8c1e584c10b2331fb184d9949c]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484125831]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485291773;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90664;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90329;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90395;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_126af8cf3a3f6b6779de41ba83b456a2]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_a96e1945f52d13dd0c35df1edfabd55f]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:0;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quantum Trading: Goldman Sachs Emerges into the Field of AI</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-quantum-trading-goldman-sachs-emerges-into-the-field-of-ai</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 08:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blair.goldenberg]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=93112</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Quantum Trading</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Goldman Sachs Finally Investing in Quantum Trading</li>
 	<li>Competition in the Quantum Trading Sector</li>
</ul>
“<em>We’re going from </em>a world<em> where people give machines rules to </em>a world<em> where people give machines problems and the machines learn how to solve them on their own."</em>” <em>- </em>Heath Terry – Head of Internet Research, Goldman Sachs

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="size-full wp-image-93163 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Goldman-Sachs-Logo.jpeg" alt="goldman-sachs-logo" width="480" height="235" /></a>

&nbsp;

<strong>Goldman Sachs Finally Investing in Quantum Trading</strong>

The Goldman Sachs Group, Inc. is a leading global investment banking, securities, and investment management firm that provides a wide range of financial services to a substantial and diversified client base that includes corporations, financial institutions, governments and individuals. Founded in 1869, the firm is headquartered in New York and maintains offices in all major financial centers around the world.

In the past, Goldman Sachs hasn't had much luck with quantum trading, keeping the company focused on human picked trades. However, recently Goldman is beginning to reinvest into artificial intelligence hedge funds, trying to secure a position in the top three funds in sales. The company aims to increase speed and efficiency within quantum trading, which has been the main driving force in the AI world, increasing the importance of this investment. Goldman is coming in pretty late in the game, where competition in the field has already weeded out less successful AI systems, making the top companies more experienced and trusted. However, Goldman has been in the financial industry since 1869 and many of these AI companies came around during the tech age. No matter how advanced these top AI hedge funds are, Goldman can catch up and surpass them with ease.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93165" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/pexels-photo.jpg" alt="Quantum Trading" width="607" height="402" /></a>

<strong>Competition in the Quantum Trading Sector</strong>

Goldman Sachs biggest competitors in the quantum trading sector are Two Sigma and the Renaissance Technologies' <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-artificial-intelligence-taking-over-hedge-fund-markets">Medallion Fund</a>. Two Sigma manages $40 billion in assets and relies on Deutsche Bank as their broker. The Medallion Fund manages $36 billion in assets and also uses Deutsche Bank as well as JP Morgan and Morgan Stanley as their brokers.

Goldman Sachs hired Mahajan, an engineering firm, to move the company in the quantum trading field in 2015 and has completed most of the improvements in 2016. Also in that timespan, Goldman has strengthened their AI structure to allow about 130 systems to analyze information about "compliance, risk, and auditing on every trade" (Retrieved from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-01-10/goldman-makes-play-for-quant-funds-in-electronic-trading-reboot">Bloomberg Markets</a>).

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-93166" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/c12ee0f379643a278198b2086afd3b9c.jpg" alt="c12ee0f379643a278198b2086afd3b9c" width="365" height="244" /></a>

Investment into AI trading has garnished new plans. The first is to persuade other quantum hedge funds that specialize in risk-aversion to partner with Goldman Sachs. Additionally, Goldman plans on working with their existing client base who have already used human-based trading to begin using quantum based trading.

Because Goldman Sachs has an existing client base, certain fees to the consumer won't apply as they don't have to outsource to another exchange. This would reduce any costs on the consumer side, making their quantum trading more attractive to consumers. One obstacle that Goldman Sachs may encounter is finding quant funds that will begin business with them, not because of negative connotations but because quant funds are nervous about moving their existing business. They're nervous because they may encounter problems such as computer glitches as well as any other operational problems. This will not be a huge problem for Goldman Sachs, as any quant fund would be lucky to link up with the such a respected banking company.

<strong>Goldman Sach's AI Expansion Vision</strong>

Earlier in December 2016, Henry Terry, the Head of Internet Research, Goldman Sachs research, released a video, explaining in more detail the effects of AI on the business world and how Goldman is expanding AI development in its investment areas. He explains that Artifical Intelligence is growing at an exponential rate as a result of three factors:
<ol>
 	<li>Massiv data proliferation, where Big Data continues to grow and is expected to grow at a 36% compound rate in the amount of data over the next five years.</li>
 	<li>Growth in the speed of computing power has increased over the past decade.</li>
 	<li>An increase in the development of open source algorithms, whereas programmers are able to build off past work to improve on a set of algorithms and not start from scratch.</li>
</ol>
As a result of these factors, there is has been a positive externality for consumers whereas he refers to it as a consumer base effect. The development in AI and Deep Learning has allowed consumers to be able to enjoy a wide range of new applications over the past decade such as Siri, Alexa, new automated traffic navigation; and even facebook tagging, which has its own machine learning capabilities.

The main areas that Goldman Sachs is investing to further develop and incorporate AI are in the Healthcare Sector and Retail Sector. In the Healthcare Sector, AI is being used to help better diagnose diseases more accurately and allowing drug developers the ability to develop systems that reduce operational costs. As the Retail Sector is moving away from the traditional brick and mortar establishment, retailers are using AI technology to better understand consumers' needs and wants in order to better predict future trends.

<strong>Conclusion</strong>

Goldman Sachs will have no trouble gaining speed within the AI trading field. The company has been around for more than 100 years and isn't going away anytime soon, the fact that they waited a few years to begin investing in AI doesn't discredit their experience and it doesn't mean they can't match or surpass their new competition.

For more information on AI in the Financial Industry, click the links below:

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-hedge-funds-with-machine-learning-capabilities">AI Hedge Fund</a>:  Hedge Funds With Machine Learning Capabilities

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-bridgewater-using-ai-to-increase-profits-and-productivity">AI Hedge Fund</a>:  Bridgewater Using AI to Increase Profits and Productivity

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-ai-hedge-fund-artificial-intelligence-taking-over-hedge-fund-markets">AI Hedge Fund</a>:  Artificial Intelligence Taking over Hedge Fund Markets

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/machine-learning-hedge-fund-artificial-intelligence-algotrading-and-hedge-funds">Machine Learning Hedge Fund</a>:  Artificial Intelligence, Algotrading and Hedge Funds

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-arbitrage-how-hedge-funds-should-use-ai-based-algorithms-for-arbitrage-trading">Arbitrage Trading</a>:  How Hedge Funds Should Use AI Based Algorithms For Arbitrage Trading

<a href="https://iknowfirst.com/algar-ai-algorithmic-based-hedge-fund-why-hedge-funds-should-adapt-with-technology-to-continue">Quant Hedge Fund</a>:  Why Hedge Funds Should Adapt AI Technology To Continue

&nbsp;
<p class="postitle"></p>


<hr />

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="alignleft wp-image-50382" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/lll.png" alt="Blair" width="70" height="73" />The article was written by Blair Goldenberg, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled in a Masters of Finance at Colorado State University.</em>
<h2>Quantum Trading</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Goldman Sachs Finally Investing in Quantum Trading</li>
 	<li>Competition in the Quantum Trading Sector</li>
</ul>

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-quantum-trading-goldman-sachs-emerges-into-the-field-of-ai"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-quantum-trading-goldman-sachs-emerges-into-the-field-of-ai">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93112</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-19 10:38:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-19 08:38:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-quantum-trading-goldman-sachs-emerges-into-the-field-of-ai]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ai"><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="artificial-intelligence"><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="blair-goldenberg"><![CDATA[blair goldenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="goldman-sachs"><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="hedge-fund"><![CDATA[Hedge Fund]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="quantum-trading"><![CDATA[quantum trading]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Quantum Trading]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Quantum Trading]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[78]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485306719;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91209;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90763;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:90395;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_b65f64de379b12896fb4bdd7654ccf5d]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_35f27d238277ecca8a5c37c3a7e5b7f1]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:2;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Apple Stock Forecast : SWOT Analysis of Apple</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-apple-stock-forecast-swot-analysis-of-apple</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 08:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Barbara]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=93225</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="s1"><i><img class="size-full wp-image-93331 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/IMG_3270.png" alt="IMG_3270" width="50" height="50" />Barbara Chouraqui, is a Junior Financial Analyst at </i><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><span class="s2"><i>I Know First</i></span></a><i>, </i></span><span class="s3"><i>and enrolled in B.A. in Business at the Institut Superieur de Gestion -ISG, Paris, France.</i></span>
<h1 class="postitle">Apple Stock Forecast</h1>
<strong>Summary
</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Apple is criticized for its pace of innovation</li>
 	<li>Big companies became one of the most important clients of Apple</li>
 	<li>Despite a tough competition, Samsung is still behind</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish on AAPL</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93227 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-15-at-2.12.21-pm.png" alt="Apple Stock Forecast" width="524" height="337" /></a>

&nbsp;

<strong><u>Strengths:</u> </strong>

Apple is benefiting from an effective innovation process and a strong ability to renew its products.

The company launched a wide range of products as phones, computers, tablets (iPad), headphones and watches. Their strong brand image is accompanied by a real infatuation for the release of new products, considered as “events”. The brand is consumer-driven and make high profit margins.

Moreover, the brand appeal of the company makes of it one of the only one in its field to be considered as a luxury brand –being offered by the richest Chinese men and women according to the Chinese group Hurun research, beating Hermès and Louis Vuitton.

Customers of Apple are very loyal to the brand.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93232 size-large" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/IPHONE-555x371.png" width="555" height="371" /></a>

The direct competitor of Apple is Samsung. However, the Korean telecommunication company encountered some problems related to their last product, the Samsung Galaxy S7. Several explosions of the phone caused by the battery of the devices have been reported. Thus, Samsung had to call its products back. This confirms the position of Apple products as the most secure and reliable products on the market.

The company permanently renews itself. In a constant willing of progress, their next iPhone will have a new design that will improve quality control's stability while enabling cheaper costs for Apple (<a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20170109PD202.html">Digitimes</a>). The next iPhone could skip the traditional "S" version that follows each release of new phones by Apple and might be the iPhone 10 instead of 8 (<a href="https://apple-stock-news.com/2017/01/apple-stock-news-a-look-into-iphone-8/">Apple Stock News: A Look into iPhone 8</a>).

The company even started to anchor its business into Corporate Social Responsibility –CSR and thus develop harmless solutions. They are also committed to environmental issues, and more particularly in the recycle process.

Finally, Apple is particularly known for being at the cutting edge of technology. Added to a specific design and a leadership position on the market, the strengths of Apple seems infinite.

<strong><u>Weaknesses:</u></strong>

However, prices of Apple products are really expensive compared to its competitors. Its main one is Samsung, using the system of Android. As an example, the iPhone 6 with 16 GB storage was as expensive as the Samsung Galaxy S6 which is enjoying a 32 GB storage. Furthermore, Apple products are not compatible with the products of other brands, but only with the other products of the brand itself.

Apple’s products are distributed through Apple website, Apple stores, electronic shops either physical –Darty, or online –Amazon.com. The exposure to Apple product is pretty low even though their presence on the media seems effective.

Apple has developed a lot of products and used its customers to highly qualitative products. With the technology advances and the rapid renewal of products, the expectations of Apple’s customers became particularly high and meet them is a challenge for the company as well as a weakness. There’s a risk of stagnation for the company and one of its competitors played on it in its last advertising, drawing attention to the stagnation of the market: core products stay the same and there are only incremental changes. Many products have been already developed by the brand and there’s a risk of stagnation.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93246 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/16510681754_992db42acb_b.jpg" alt="Apple Stock Forecast" width="1024" height="682" /></a>

<strong><u>Opportunities: </u></strong>

That’s why the company should take advantages of the opportunities it has, firstly regarding the diversification of products.

Even though the product portfolio of the company is already well filled, it’s a necessity for the company to keep the attention and the loyalty of its customers by offering them the products they want. The market of connected objects is growing rapidly and is planned to represent 21 billion by 2020 according to the research company Gartner. And the smart watches of Apple received a particularly good welcoming from consumers: they already represent 50% of the market share of smart watches in the US.

One track for Apple could be to develop the watch, but also other connected devices in home automation and sport. Another one could also be to develop its partnerships.

The company encountered many critics regarding its current pace of innovation. However, the brand already enjoys valuable business partnerships with prestigious brands as AT&amp;T –an American telecommunication conglomerate, Foxconn Technology group –world’s largest electronic manufacturer or TPK Holding –world’s largest touch-panel suppliers. According to the New-York Times, Apple’s products are the preferred devices for corporations. Thus, companies represent important customers of Apple (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/08/technology/once-taunted-by-steve-jobs-companies-are-now-big-customers-of-apple.html?_r=1">New York Times</a>).

Recently British Airways bought 17,000 iPads for its staff, IBM developed 100 enterprise apps for over 2 000 companies. iPhones and iPads are used by companies because it’s seen as more secure than the system of Android. Among the different qualities of the Apple’s products, its good management of hardware and software is particularly appreciated. With new partnerships, Apple would not only benefit from better exposure; alliances are also a way for them to improve their products both on the management and the security of the devices.

<strong><u>Threats: </u></strong>

Apple does not only have to deal with criticism regarding its pace of innovation. It also faces a certain amount of threats as a really tough competition on its market. They differentiate themselves quite well for the moment and, as stated before, the recent scandal toward the last Samsung should help them to strengthen their leadership position on the market.

Competition is also accompanied by imitation of the company. As an example, Apple filed a lawsuit against Samsung for infringement of design patents. This case was judged by the Supreme court and proves the tension of the market.

Last but not least, Apple has to tackle the rise in labor costs in the countries in which they relocate their plants.

&nbsp;

<strong>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish on AAPL </strong>

&nbsp;

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93235 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/APPL2.png" alt="Apple Stock Forecast" width="384" height="235" /></a>

I Know First Algorithm has previously predicted AAPL stock movement like in <a href="https://apple-stock-news.com/2017/01/fr-apple-stock-prediction-based-on-self-learning-algorithm-aapl-yields-almost-13-in-1-year/">this prediction</a> of a 1 year period from January 3, 2016, until January 3, 2017. The AAPL signal was 135.89 with a predictability of 0.3 which managed to bring returns of 12.71% in one year.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-93236" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/APPL.jpg" alt="Apple Stock Forecast" width="740" height="684" /></a>

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>
<strong>Conclusion</strong>

Despite the critics and the tough competition Apple had recently to deal with, the company succeeds to impose its brand as a key player in its field. The bullish signal identified by the algorithm is strengthened by different facts. The excitement generated for each release of Apple remains and the news carefully distilled by the company are closely followed by the market.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-93238" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Premium-Signature.png" alt="Apple Stock Forecast " width="545" height="366" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="s1"><i><img class="size-full wp-image-93331 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/IMG_3270.png" alt="IMG_3270" width="50" height="50" />Barbara Chouraqui, is a Junior Financial Analyst at </i><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><span class="s2"><i>I Know First</i></span></a><i>, </i></span><span class="s3"><i>and enrolled in B.A. in Business at the Institut Superieur de Gestion -ISG, Paris, France.</i></span>
<h1 class="postitle">Apple Stock Forecast</h1>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Apple is criticized for its pace of innovation</li>
 	<li>Big companies became one of the most important clients of Apple</li>
 	<li>Despite a tough competition, Samsung is still behind</li>
 	<li>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast for AAPL for 2017</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-apple-stock-forecast-swot-analysis-of-apple"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-apple-stock-forecast-swot-analysis-of-apple">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93225</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-17 10:14:10]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-17 08:14:10]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsrar-apple-stock-forecast-swot-analysis-of-apple]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="appl"><![CDATA[APPL]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="apple-forecast"><![CDATA[Apple Forecast]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="apple-stock-forecast"><![CDATA[Apple Stock Forecast]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="apple-swot-analysis"><![CDATA[Apple SWOT Analysis]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="barbara-chouraqui"><![CDATA[Barbara Chouraqui]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ipad"><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="samsung"><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Apple Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Apple Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[74]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485374813;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91969;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:50707;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:42334;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_98564e0c573a2632a6797e81d38cc03f]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote data-secret="ZARuVWTXnS" class="wp-embedded-content"><a href="https://apple-stock-news.com/2017/01/apple-stock-news-a-look-into-iphone-8/">Apple Stock News: A Look Into iPhone 8</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://apple-stock-news.com/2017/01/apple-stock-news-a-look-into-iphone-8/embed/#?secret=ZARuVWTXnS" data-secret="ZARuVWTXnS" width="600" height="338" title="&#8220;Apple Stock News: A Look Into iPhone 8&#8221; &#8212; Apple Stock News  |" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_98564e0c573a2632a6797e81d38cc03f]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1484556207]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:2;s:9:"pinterest";i:1;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Is ConocoPhillips a profitable investment?</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-conocophillips-profitable-investment</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 15:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marika]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=93318</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="s1"><i>
<img class="wp-image-93326 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Marika.png" alt="Marika" width="50" height="50" />by Marika Nicastro, a Junior Financial Analyst at </i><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><span class="s2"><i>I Know First</i></span></a><i>, </i></span><span class="s3"><i>and enrolled at a Business Management program at the Luiss University in Rome, Italy.</i></span>
<h2>Is ConocoPhillips a Profitable Investment?</h2>
Summary
<ul>
 	<li>OPEC agreement</li>
 	<li>Funds and investors</li>
 	<li>Conclusion
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93323" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2-300x71.png" alt="2" width="393" height="93" /></li>
</ul>
ConocoPhillips, the world’s largest independent exploration and production company. The Company explores for, produces, transports and markets crude oil, bitumen, natural gas and liquefied natural gas (LNG). The Company operates through six operating segments, which are primarily defined by geographic region: Alaska; Lower 48; Canada; Europe and North Africa; Asia Pacific and Middle East, and Other International.

<strong>OPEC Agreement</strong>

ConocoPhillips, as the other E&amp;P companies, will gain better performance thanks to the OPEC agreement. This states that OPEC will reduce output by about 1.2 million barrels a day by January fulfilling a plan sketched out in Algiers in September to cut its production to 32.5 million barrels. Saudi Arabia, which raised oil production to a record this year, will reduce output by 486,000 barrels a day to 10.058 million a day. Iraq, OPEC’s second-largest producer, agreed to cut by 210,000 barrels a day from October levels. Even non-OPEC like Russia has joined output cuts for the first time in 15 years.

The OPEC agreements caused a surge in oil prices, boosting its production, especially in the united states where the cost of the production is higher than in Saudi Arabia. This means that ConocoPhillips (NYSE:COP) could sell more and benefit from the high price, earning more cash flows.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-93324 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/3.png" alt="3" width="1141" height="552" />
(<a href="http://www.bloomberg.com">Bloomberg</a>)

However, is important to add that the supply’s increase could cause in 9/12 months a reduction of prices.

<strong>Funds and Investors</strong>

Hedge funds and other institutional investors have recently made changes to their positions in the ConocoPhillips (NYSE:COP):
- Telemus Capital LLC increased its position in shares of ConocoPhillips by 0.5% in the third quarter.
- Bahl &amp; Gaynor Inc. increased its position in shares of ConocoPhillips by 0.6% in the third quarter.
- Sequoia Financial Advisors LLC increased its position in shares of ConocoPhillips by 0.3% in the second quarter.
- Integrated Investment Consultants LLC increased its position in shares of ConocoPhillips by 2.0% in the third quarter.
- NEXT Financial Group Inc increased its position in shares of ConocoPhillips by 0.3% in the second quarter.
(<a href="http://dailyquint.com/">Dailyquit</a>)

<strong>Conclusion</strong>

The financial performance for ConocoPhillips is highly correlated to movements in Brent Crude prices. Brent averaged about $45 a barrel in 2016, and is expected to rise above $55 this year. Hence, ConocoPhillips (NYSE:COP) is supposed to be a profitable investment.

<strong> </strong><strong>I Know First Algorithmic Bullish Forecast For COP</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/1.png" width="349" height="315" /></a>

&nbsp;

<strong>I Know First Algorithm Heatmap </strong><b>Explanation</b>

The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position), the signal strength is related to the magnitude of the expected return and is used for ranking purposes of the investment opportunities.

Predictability is the actual fitness function being optimized every day, and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal. This is a unique indicator of the I Know First algorithm, allowing the user to separate and focus on the most predictable assets according to the algorithm. Ranging between -1 and 1, one should focus on predictability levels significantly above 0 in order to fill confident about/trust the signal.
<h3><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/sites/default/files/Webside%20Forecast%20Table.png" width="604" height="808" /></a></h3>

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="wp-image-93326 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Marika.png" alt="Marika" width="50" height="50" />by Marika Nicastro, a Junior Financial Analyst at </i><a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><span class="s2"><i>I Know First</i></span></a><i>, </i></span><span class="s3"><i>and enrolled at a Business Management program at the Luiss University in Rome, Italy.</em>
<h2>Is ConocoPhillips a profitable investment?</h2>
<strong>Summary</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>OPEC agreement</li>
 	<li>Funds and investors</li>
 	<li>Conclusion</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-conocophillips-profitable-investment"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsrar-conocophillips-profitable-investment">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93318</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-17 17:08:09]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-17 15:08:09]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsrar-conocophillips-profitable-investment]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="cop-conocophillips"><![CDATA[COP; ConocoPhillips;]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="marika-nicastro"><![CDATA[marika Nicastro]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1976]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_d4bbd0ed32551394136d59cfd8b67912]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_755ea6fd630166b67f901adada64444b]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Is ConocoPhillips a profitable investment?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Is ConocoPhillips a profitable investment?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485364633;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92059;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91789;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91707;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:2;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Algorithmic Forecast Performance: Analysis of Brazilian stocks with high rates of return</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/algar-algorithmic-forecast-performance-analysis-of-brazilian-stocks-with-high-rates-of-return</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 10:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[felipe]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=93503</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Algorithmic Forecast Performance</h2>
Fundamental Analysis of  Top 5 Brazilian Stocks

I Know First Stock Algorithm, along with Fundamental Analysis, generated a forecast in <a href="https://iknowfirst.com/fr-stock-market-algorithm-based-on-genetic-algorithms-returns-up-to-17-47-in-1-month">December 14th</a> with strong bullish signals of long position for 5 popular Brazilian stocks. But before the results we are going to give a quick explanation on how the forecast works.

<strong>Stock Market Prediction</strong>

The I Know First algorithm identifies waves in the stock market to forecast its trajectory. Every day the algorithm analyzes raw data to generate an updated forecast for each market. Each forecast includes 2 indicators: signal and predictability.

<strong>Signal</strong>

The signal represents the predicted movement and direction, be it an increase or decrease, for each particular asset; not a percentage or specific target price. The signal strength indicates how much the current price deviates from what the system considers an equilibrium or “fair” price.

<strong>Predictability</strong>

The predictability is the historical correlation between the past algorithmic predictions and the actual market movement for each particular asset. The algorithm then averages the results of all the historical predictions, while giving more weight to more recent performances.
Predictability (P) is obtained by calculating the correlation between the past predictions and the actual asset movement for each discrete time period. The algorithm then averages the results of all the predictions, giving more weight to more recent performances. As the machine keeps learning and amassing more data, the values of (P) generally increase.

Predictability is measured on a scale ranging from negative 1 to positive 1; this metric is an adaptation of the Pearson correlation coefficient.
P=-1 means the actual market moved in the opposite direction than the algorithm predicted.
P=0 means that there is no correlation between the prediction and the actual market movement.
P=1 means that there is perfect correlation between the actual market movement and its predicted movement.

Any value of P above zero indicates a positive predictability, the higher the better. For stocks we monitor and predict, the Predictability (P) generally ranges between P=0.2 and P=0.7.

<strong>Analysis</strong>

From now on we are going to analyze each company that had strong bullish signals in Dec. 14th.
<p style="text-align: left;"><u>1 – Vale S.A. - Metals and mining company</u></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-93504" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale-300x123.png" alt="" width="300" height="123" /></p>
<strong><u>Forecast</u></strong>

Signal 58.99

Predictability 0.55

<img class="size-medium wp-image-93617 aligncenter" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Forecast-VALE-300x133.png" alt="" width="300" height="133" />

<strong><u>The company</u></strong>

Vale is a Brazilian multinational mining company and one of the largest logistics operators in Brazil. It is the third largest mining company in the world. In the electric power sector, the company participates in consortiums and currently operates nine hydroelectric plants.

Vale has been enjoying the good moment for the mining sector with China as a big buyer of iron ore and the prices of iron ore going up (USD 51.36 in Jun 2016 to USD 79.75 in Dec 2016). The devaluation of Brazilian currency also made it easier for the company to export.

<strong><u>Fundamental Analysis</u></strong>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93559 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Fundamentos-Vale-3.png" width="528" height="272" />

Vale had interesting numbers. Despite the economic crisis in Brazil it was still able to grow its Net Profit and Net Worth. The current ratio is above 1, showing that the company had more current assets than current liabilities. Its ROE was above the mining sector average of -43%. The price/book was still reasonable since it’s not much higher than 1, the trailing P/E was low and it might indicate a good bargain to buy stocks, especially when the forward p/e is pointing to a huge appreciation of the company in the future.

<strong><u>Conclusion</u></strong>

After the Fundamental Analysis and the scenario, it can be seen that this stock had presented an optimistic forecast, as the algorithm fore shown. The recommended position was for 1 month, and the results are below:

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93534 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale-gráfico-2.png" width="1099" height="363" />

&nbsp;

Vale’s stock grew 1.09 USD in about one month.  The algorithm results were 12.84%.

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align: left;"><u>2 – SID (Companhia Siderúrgica Nacional) -  Company engaged in the steel industry</u></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-93508" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CSN-300x135.png" alt="" width="300" height="135" /></p>
<strong><u>Forecast</u></strong>

Signal 92.58

Predictability 0.49

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93612 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Forecast-SID-2-300x133.png" width="300" height="133" /></a>

&nbsp;

<strong><u>The company</u></strong>

Companhia Siderúrgica Nacional (CSN) is the largest steel industry in Brazil and Latin America. It controls companies, such as CSN Paraná, Metallic, Namisa and has equity participations in MRS Logística, Transnordestina Logística and others.

Similarly to Vale, CSN has been enjoying the good moment for the mining sector with China as a big buyer of iron ore and the prices going up, at the same time that Brazilian currency is devaluating, making it easier to export.

<strong><u>Fundamental Analysis</u></strong>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93560 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Fundamentos-CSN-3.png" width="534" height="278" />

CSN’s current ratio is good. Its operating profit was incredibly big, being much higher than the net worth of the company, and showing the potential growth of the company still to come. Despite the negative net profit, the net worth of the company grew 148% when compared to the previous year, which might indicate the acquisition of assets for future projects. ROE is negative, however, is still above the sector’s average. The price/book and the trailing P/E show that the company might have been slightly overvaluated and trailing annual dividend yield shows that the company has not been paying dividends which are bad signs. Still, its aggressive Beta pointed to a high increase of the stock value, since the Bovespa was pointed to go up.

<strong><u>Conclusion</u></strong>

After the Fundamental Analysis and the scenario, it can be seen that this stock had presented an optimistic forecast, as the algorithm fore shown. The recommended position was for 1 month, and the results are below:

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93540 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale-gráfico-2-1.png" width="1089" height="403" />

CSN’s stock grew 0.54 USD in about one month.  The algorithm results were 16.77%.

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align: left;"><u>3 – BAK (Braskem) - Produces thermoplastic resins</u></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-93511" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Braskem-300x48.png" alt="" width="300" height="48" /></p>
<strong><u>Forecast</u></strong>

Signal 89.53

Predictability 0.23

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93613 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Forecast-BAK-300x133.png" width="300" height="133" /></a>

<strong><u>The company</u></strong>

Braskem, controlled by Organização Odebrecht (Odebrecht Organization) with expressive participation of Petrobras, is a Brazilian chemical and petrochemical company. It stands out for being the global leader in biopolymers production and the biggest producer of thermoplastic resins in the Americas.

Braskem is the largest producer of polyethylene, polypropylene and PVC in Brazil. The company is also the leader in the US polypropylene market and has a big production capacity in Germany.

Alaska (investment fund in Brazil) started building a stake in petrochemicals maker Braskem about four months ago. Barros (CEO) likes the company because it is fundamentally sound and valuations are low, Braskem’s price-to-earnings ratio is 8.3, less than half the level three years ago, he said (Dec/2016).

<strong><u>Fundamental Analysis</u></strong>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93561 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Fundamentos-Braskem-3.png" width="537" height="271" />

Current Ratio is above 1. The operating profit has been tremendously big in the periods, being much larger than the net worth of the company and showing its true potential. The net profit was really bigger than the net worth and the ROE was easy above the sector’s average.  Price/Book and Trailing P/E are saying that the company might be overpriced, however, it does happen often when the company has solid fundaments and a good perception of investors, so this is why its price is up. Trailing annual dividend yield is good and Beta just shows that the company is strongly tied with the evolution of the market.

<strong><u>Conclusion</u></strong>

After the Fundamental Analysis and the scenario, it can be seen that this stock had presented an optimistic forecast, as the algorithm fore shown. The recommended position was for 1 month, and the results are below:

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93545 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale-gráfico-2-2.png" alt="Algorithmic Forecast Performance" width="1093" height="402" />

Braskem’s stock grew 2.23 USD in about one month.  The algorithm results were 11.25%.

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align: left;"><u>4 – GGB (Gerdau) -  Manufacturer of long steel in the North and South America</u></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-93514" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Gerdau-300x86.png" alt="" width="300" height="86" /></p>
<strong><u>Forecast</u></strong>

Signal 5.59

Predictability 0.63

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93615 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Forecast-GGB-1-300x133.png" width="300" height="133" /></a>

&nbsp;

<strong><u>The company</u></strong>

Gerdau is a Brazilian steel company. It has industrial operations in 14 countries - in the Americas, Europe and Asia - with an installed capacity of more than 25 million tons per year. It is the largest recycler in Latin America and, worldwide, it transforms millions of tons of scrap annually into steel.

<strong><u>Fundamental Analysis</u></strong>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93563 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Fundamentos-Gerdau-3-1.png" width="531" height="272" />

Gerdau’s current ratio was excellent, having almost 3 times more current assets than current liabilities. Operating profit incredibly high and net profit recovering from the strong negative result in 2015. Its ROE is above the steel sector’s average of -17%. The Price/Book and also the trailing P/E indicate that it should be an excellent moment to buy the stock with a huge bargain. Trailing annual dividend yield is low, but it’s the start of a recovery from last year disaster. This Beta indicates that with the growth of the market it might jump even higher.

<strong><u>Conclusion</u></strong>

After the Fundamental Analysis and the scenario, it can be seen that this stock had presented an optimistic forecast, as the algorithm fore shown. The recommended position was for 1 month, and the results are below:

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93548 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale-gráfico-2-3.png" width="1088" height="402" />

Gerdau’s stock grew 0.53 USD in about one month.  The algorithm results were 15.06%.

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align: left;"><u>5 – TSU (Tim Participações S.A.) - Provider of mobile telecommunication services</u></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-93517" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/TIM-300x99.png" alt="" width="300" height="99" /></p>
<strong><u>Forecast</u></strong>

Signal 42.29

Predictability 0.57

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93616 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Forecast-TSU-300x133.png" width="300" height="133" /></a>

<strong><u>The company</u></strong>

Tim Participações is a Brazilian telephone company subsidiary of Telecom Italia. In Brazil, it was founded in 1998, but its network concept occurred in 2002, when its coverage had already reached the level of 2,500 cities. It pioneered the launch of EDGE technology in the country. TIM became the second largest cell phone company in Brazil in terms of number of customers and leader in net service revenue. In August 2015 the company had 73.38 million (26.21%) of active lines in the country.

<strong><u>Fundamental Analysis</u></strong>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93564 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Fundamentos-TIM-3.png" width="529" height="272" />

Tim had a good current ratio. The operating profit was almost as big as the whole company’s net worth. Net profit decreased strongly when compared to 2015, however, it's still positive. Despite the decrease in net profit, Tim was still able to gain net worth. Price/Book and Trailing P/E indicate that the company might be strongly overpriced, but when we look to Forward P/E, it’s possible to see that it might even become more expensive, so even with the high prices, it is a bullish prediction. Dividends were low, as expected with a smaller net profit.

<strong><u>Conclusion</u></strong>

After the Fundamental Analysis and the scenario, it can be seen that this stock had presented an optimistic forecast, as the algorithm fore shown. The recommended position was for 1 month, and the results are below:

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-93549 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Vale-gráfico-2-4.png" width="1094" height="408" />

Tim’s stock grew 1.26 USD in about one month. The algorithm results were 10.07%.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Algorithmic Performance: Analysis of Brazilian stocks with high rates of return]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93503</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-24 12:04:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-24 10:04:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[algar-algorithmic-forecast-performance-analysis-of-brazilian-stocks-with-high-rates-of-return]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="i-know-first-reviews"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Performance]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="bak"><![CDATA[BAK]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="braskem"><![CDATA[Braskem]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="brazil"><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="brazilian-stocks"><![CDATA[brazilian stocks]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="csn"><![CDATA[csn]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="fundamentalist"><![CDATA[Fundamentalist]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="gerdau"><![CDATA[Gerdau]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ggb"><![CDATA[GGB]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="sid"><![CDATA[SID]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tim"><![CDATA[tim]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tsu"><![CDATA[TSU]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="vale"><![CDATA[Vale]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[75]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[38]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Algorithmic Forecast Performance]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Algorithmic Forecast Performance]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[80]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485347548;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:1368;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:10907;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:10652;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_dont_email_post_to_subs]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[algorithmic-performance-analysis-brazilian-stocks-high-rates-return]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dpsp_networks_shares]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:11:"google-plus";i:0;s:9:"pinterest";i:0;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_encloseme]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Nike Stock Forecast: BCG Matrix &amp; SWOT Indicate Long Term Value</title>
		<link>https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-nike-stock-forecast-bcg-matrix-swot-indicate-long-term-value</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 14:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shabotinsky]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iknowfirst.com/?p=93570</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="wp-image-42826 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Profile-Picutre-real-300x300.png" width="50" height="50" />This article was written by David Shabotinsky, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled at the undergraduate Finance program at the Interdisciplinary Center, Herzliya.</em>
<h2>Nike Stock Forecast<strong> </strong></h2>
Summary
<ul>
 	<li>Background on Nike Inc. and its business strategy</li>
 	<li>BCG Matrix Analysis using product segments</li>
 	<li>SWOT Analysis on Nike Inc.</li>
 	<li>I Know First's self-learning algorithm maintains a bullish forecast on NKE shares</li>
</ul>
<strong> </strong><strong>Background</strong>

NIKE, Inc. (NKE), together with its subsidiaries, designs, develops, markets, and sells athletic footwear, apparel, equipment, and accessories worldwide. It offers products in nine categories, including running, NIKE basketball, the Jordan brand, football, men’s training, women’s training, action sports, sportswear, and golf. (Yahoo Finance).

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-93604 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-24-at-4.20.16-PM.png" width="262" height="184" /></a>

Nike was founded in 1964, with the initial intention of selling running shoes. As time went on, their product range widened to apparel for common sports, such as basketball and leisure wear. In 1976 Nike had reached revenues of $14 million and went public in 1980, initially offering 2 million shares of stock. By 1997, the stock hit an all-time high at a price of $76 a share. Then, in 2003, Nike purchased Converse. Earlier in 2016, at a shareholder meeting, CEO Mark Parker set a goal to reach $50 billion in sales by 2020. NKE expects to do so through continual product development, further market penetration in emerging markets, and increasing focus on its women’s division.

Nike, a brand that many athletes and non-athletes have come to use to define premium quality athletic products and services. The firm has seen much growth in its business strategy development and brand recognition over the past couple decades. They had begun to shift their efforts and targeting the higher end market in the athletic apparel industry to become the dominant premium brand (above Adidas).  The brand of Nike is no longer representative of even athletic apparel, rather they have managed to create an idea that they are able to help individuals overcome obstacles. This can be seen in almost any Nike commercial, whereas the main idea is not advertising the specific shoe or other product, rather the idea of overcoming obstacles. Nike’s income has risen tremendously over the past decade. For example, in 2015, they had reported a net income of $3.27 billion, up from the previous year’s income of $2.69 billion. In addition to the operational activity it is important examine how much the company actually earned in cash to ‘take to the bank’. Their cash has as well increased tremendously to 3.85 billion in 2015, from 2.22 billion in 2014.

<strong>Nike's Value Creation </strong>

In general, there are two main avenues to achieve a competitive advantage, either through cost leadership or differentiation. Today, Nike mainly practices product differentiation on the user-end to its consumers, as it offers premium products at a higher-end price. For a firm to achieve a real competitive value, it does so through the follow: <strong>Value= Utility – Cost</strong>.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://wildchildsports.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/nike-quotes-we-are-all-witnesses.jpg" width="513" height="385" /></a>
<h6><strong><em>(Source: http://wildchildsports.com)</em></strong></h6>
By offering the highest utility to consumers, Nike has been able to control the market share in the foot apparel industry, and thus one of its main competitive advantages is its brand equity. In the 1990s, Nike had implemented a cost leadership strategy to regain market share it had greatly lost. Today, it has been able to successfully implement both aspects, which is rare. A huge competitive advantage of Nike is that it does not own any factories for production, rather outsources operations to hundreds of factories in countries like China, and maintains very tight supply chain control. Through its supply chain management, it is able to lower costs of production, while maintaining its high standards. Additionally, it also lowers its inventory risk, because if a trend in the market changes it is able to change inventory faster. Another main advantage that it has is its ambitious R&amp;D and product development. Nike operates in approximately 180 countries and is able constantly introduce new product lines with successful expansion. The use of prominent athletes, adds to its brand image. One of Nike’s most valuable resource/capabilities are its financial ones. Nike has a consistent overall revenue growth and dividend payout to shareholders. It as well has a large amount of retained earnings leftover as it's able to develop top line athletic products.

<strong>BCG Analysis for Nike Inc. </strong>

In order to better understand the market position of Nike and whether they can capitalize on their products, one can use a BCG matrix analysis to divide the various product segments and benchmark their performance to their largest competitor(s). The data gathered is directly from Nike’s most recent 10k form, and the product segment division is Footwear, Apparel, and Equipment.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93600 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-24-at-12.51.47-PM.png" width="1258" height="399" /></a>
<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93602 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-07-at-10.12.51-PM.png" alt="Nike Stock Forecast " width="761" height="588" /></a>

More on what a BCG Matrix can be <a href="http://www.smartinsights.com/marketing-planning/marketing-models/use-bcg-matrix/">found here</a>.

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93601 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-07-at-10.13.07-PM.png" width="615" height="189" /></a>

The data was taken from Nike Inc. and Adidas' 10k forms, and the market share was determined by revenue of each firm as they represent the top firms in the industry. Additionally, market growth was determined by taking revenue growth for various firms and comparing them to Nike's growth in each of the segments chosen.

<strong>SWOT Analysis for NKE</strong>

Strengths:
<ul>
 	<li>Brand Equity (intangible assets), since it controls the largest market share in its industry and sells high-end premium products to consumers. It is able to retain top athletes such as Lebron James, which adds to consumers taste. It understands as well which athletes to cover and how to exploit value from athletics. Its partnership with Michael Jordan has continued to heavily payoff, mainly through shoe sales.</li>
 	<li>Supply chain management, since it does it own any physical locations it can move and outsource to improve operations with more ease. Additionally, it practices a ‘make to stock’ strategy in its supply so it is able to provide customers with the most readily and fashionable available goods.</li>
 	<li>R&amp;D, the firm invests heavily in product development so it's able to offer premium products. It owns top doctors, specialists and other scientists from around the world to develop enhanced performance athletic wear.</li>
</ul>
Weaknesses:
<ul>
 	<li>Poor consumer perception from labor practices, in that Nike’s image can be damaged as a result of its efforts to outsource to cheaper alternative manufacturers who are more known for poor labor practice. A poor public image can hurt Nike’s sales.</li>
 	<li>Nike charges high prices for its products, which hurts the purchasing power of its consumer. As Nike enters more emerging market countries consumers will be much more price sensitive, especially those poorer population sets. Additionally, it sells heavily to retails who themselves are price sensitive also. The price sensitivity especially becomes risky when entering recessionary downturns in the economy.</li>
</ul>
<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://images.businessfinancenews.com/bfn/960-adidas-ag-adr-challenges-nike-inc-with-the-acquisition-of-runtastic.jpg" width="960" height="540" /></a>
<h6><strong>(Source: businessfinancenews.com)</strong></h6>
Opportunities:
<ul>
 	<li>Emerging markets, while markets in OECD nations like America have become more saturated Nike still has much room to grow in bigger population countries like China and India. Its product portfolio would need to be adjusted to fit the needs of those in China’s economy for example, and it can use its strong R&amp;D to do so.</li>
 	<li>Horizontal integration into other high-end products such as sunglasses and jewelry.</li>
 	<li>Product development, since the company is known for innovation. Furthermore, it can use its financial resources to acquire innovative smaller brands.</li>
</ul>
Threats:
<ul>
 	<li>International trade, since it trades in 180 countries it is heavily exposed to exchange rate risks and other underlying risks from global trade.</li>
 	<li>Competition is very high in Nike’s industry which can squeeze its margins. For example, Under Armour and Lululemon are newer brands gaining high popularity.</li>
 	<li>General market trends can change over time, and thus Nike must constantly innovate to stay on top.</li>
</ul>
<strong>I Know First’s Algorithmic Prediction for NKE</strong>

<a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-93607 size-full" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/NKE-Forecast-IKF-.png" width="502" height="308" /></a>

I Know First's self-learning algorithm maintains a bullish forecast on NKE over a 1 month, 3 months, and 1-year horizon. For the 1 year horizon, the algorithm has a signal strength and predictability indicator of 56.23 and 0.65, respectively. The sign of the signal tells in which direction the asset price is expected to go (positive = to go up = Long, negative = to drop = Short position). The Predictability indicator is the actual fitness function being optimized every day and can be simplified explained as the correlation based quality measure of the signal.

<strong>Conclusion</strong>

The strong brand equity and financial health of Nike Inc. create a great value play in the long run. Using a SWOT analysis and BCG Matrix, one can determine the best product segments and the key advantages that Nike is offering to investors. The three main segments that Nike competes in are either a ‘star’ or ‘cash cow’, showing how strong of a market position and revenue it generates from them. I Know First’s self-learning algorithm maintains a bullish outlook on NKE shares in the long-term as well.

<hr />

<a href="http://iknowfirst.com/category/premium"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-30416 size-medium" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="300" height="202" /></a>

<hr />

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[<em><img class="wp-image-42826 alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Profile-Picutre-real-300x300.png" width="50" height="50" />This article was written by David Shabotinsky, a Financial Analyst at <a href="http://iknowfirst.com/stock-forecast-algorithm">I Know First</a>, and enrolled at the undergraduate Finance program at the Interdisciplinary Center, Herzliya.</em>
<h2>Nike Stock Forecast<strong> </strong></h2>
Summary
<ul>
 	<li>Background on Nike Inc. and its business strategy</li>
 	<li>BCG Matrix Analysis using product segments</li>
 	<li>SWOT Analysis on Nike Inc.</li>
 	<li>I Know First's self-learning algorithm maintains a bullish forecast on NKE shares</li>
</ul>


<h2><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-nike-stock-forecast-bcg-matrix-swot-indicate-long-term-value"><img class="wp-image-30416  alignleft" src="https://iknowfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/PREMIUM-FINAL-300x202.png" alt="premium" width="103" height="69" />Read The Full Premium Article</a><a href="https://iknowfirst.com/rsar-nike-stock-forecast-bcg-matrix-swot-indicate-long-term-value">
</a></h2>

Subscribe to receive exclusive PREMIUM content <a href="http://lpage.iknowfirst.com/">here</a>]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93570</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-01-24 16:17:14]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-01-24 14:17:14]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[rsar-nike-stock-forecast-bcg-matrix-swot-indicate-long-term-value]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="adidas"><![CDATA[Adidas]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="algorithmic-articles"><![CDATA[Algorithmic Articles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="athletic-apparel"><![CDATA[Athletic Apparel]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="bcg-matrix"><![CDATA[BCG Matrix]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="brand-equity"><![CDATA[Brand Equity]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="david-shabotinsky"><![CDATA[David Shabotinsky]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nike-inc"><![CDATA[Nike Inc.]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="nke"><![CDATA[NKE]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="premium"><![CDATA[Premium]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="swot-analysis"><![CDATA[swot analysis]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Nike Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Nike Stock Forecast]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[80]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_jetpack_related_posts_cache]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:32:"8f6677c9d6b0f903e98ad32ec61f8deb";a:2:{s:7:"expires";i:1485375111;s:7:"payload";a:3:{i:0;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:42825;}i:1;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:91178;}i:2;a:1:{s:2:"id";i:92133;}}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_b60bf31e50350ccbff1e7bc048a06290]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_1eb6d684959b8dee10271edcddfb258a]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_3b5f1913819b7686303a4f75f4607f76]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_2f6fd09a4e2e11765e35ab1fc052fc53]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[videolink]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
